<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> 
 <title>CaptNemo.in</title>
 <link href="http://captnemo.in/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://captnemo.in/"/>
 <updated>2012-09-08T01:02:49+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://captnemo.in</id>
 <author>
   <name>Abhay Rana</name>
   <email>capt.n3m0@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Things I expect in a Chrome/iOS update</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/07/14/chrome-ios/"/>
   <updated>2012-07-14T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/07/14/chrome-ios</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've changed to using Chrome for iOS as my primary browser. Since I only own an iPad 2, all of my observations are with regard to the iPad version of the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Why I love Chrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chrome is already my primary browser on my primary machine, and after it came out for the iOS, I tried it out hesitantly, but to my surprise (contrary to what the internet says) it is working out even better than expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to sync tabs across my laptop and tablet. I can leave my laptop and continue reading on the go. I don't own a Mac, so I can't comment against how Safari/iCloud does it, but it works well enough for me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All my desktop bookmarks (and bookmarklets) are available and functioning instantly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Omnibox is awesome, and saves me a lot of trouble, looking in my history, bookmarks, and pre-fetching stuff. This was the most important feature that Chrome v1 brought along with it (when it was released in Windows), and its nice to find it work exactly as indended.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incognito Mode (I previously used Dolphin in private mode, but this is far better).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete bookmark listing while creating a new bookmark. Unlike Desktop version of Chrome, which only shows 5 most recently used folders. I bookmark stuff extensively, and it makes the process much easier for me than on the desktop version, ironically. &lt;a href=&quot;/img/bookmark_compare.png&quot;&gt;See Image for Comparision&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tab Switching is brilliant. It seems to be inspired/copied straight from &lt;a href=&quot;http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/paper-by-fiftythree/id506003812?mt=8&quot;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;, but it is executed well enough for me. It gets better once you get used to it. The tag bar itself is scrollable as a plus (you can hide/unhide tabs). I've read people complaining about this, but it helps me browse on the ipad one-handed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It feels fast, especially after continous use. I don't know if its the ported networking stack, or better caching, but page load speeds are better than Safari for me in general.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: If you have a jailbroken device, you can setup Chrome as your default browser using BrowserChooser from Cydia. The best part is that home-screen shortcuts open in Chrome as well.  I've ditched Facebook App for a shortcut icon to &lt;code&gt;touch.facebook.com&lt;/code&gt; as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Things I want&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for &lt;strong&gt;configurable search engines&lt;/strong&gt;. I use them extensively (for eg &lt;strong&gt;d&lt;/strong&gt;uckduckgo, google &lt;strong&gt;l&lt;/strong&gt;ucky search, &lt;strong&gt;a&lt;/strong&gt;mazon, &lt;strong&gt;e&lt;/strong&gt;bay, &lt;strong&gt;g&lt;/strong&gt;it&lt;strong&gt;h&lt;/strong&gt;ub, &lt;strong&gt;s&lt;/strong&gt;tack&lt;strong&gt;o&lt;/strong&gt;verflow and even google &lt;strong&gt;m&lt;/strong&gt;obile search). The pre-defined search engines are of no use to me (Bing/Yahoo/Guruji).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find in Page&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a no-brainer. &lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: This is available via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.addictivetips.com/ios/great-cydia-tweaks-for-chrome-iphone-ipad/&quot;&gt;Chrome Customizer&lt;/a&gt; in Cydia for a jailbroken device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to &lt;strong&gt;turn off images/javascript&lt;/strong&gt;) (Content Settings). I'm not sure if it will be possible w/o proxying like how Opera does, but this would be nice to have (since people might want to save bandwidth on 3g).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for emailing an entire page (rendered).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UserScript support&lt;/strong&gt;. I don't know if apple would allow it at all, but I think the Apple ToS disallows code to be downloaded. What if there were some sort of linking support to allow me to insert some external script tag?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Readability/iReader&lt;/strong&gt; like support. The safari readability link does work wonders. This could be simulated with a bookmarklet, but once again calling them is hard. &lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: ChromeCustomizer can do this via settings menu (see below).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better access to bookmarks/bookmarklets&lt;/strong&gt;. At least show me the mobile bookmarks so I can keep them separate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wait a bit more before taking the page snapshot for the speed-dial. The GMail snapshot has always been blank for me. At least check if the snapshot is completely blank, and wait a bit more if that is the case.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;App shortcuts. The kind like you get for almost all websites on Chrome Webstore. I think they are referred to as &lt;strong&gt;&quot;Chrome Apps&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; against &quot;Extensions&quot;, which would be completely disallowed as per Apple ToS. Since Apps are just shortcuts and some icons, they should be allowed in some manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better history&lt;/strong&gt; support. Seeing just the last 6 closed tabs kind of sucks. Give me some real history browser (and improve the one in desktop chrome while you're at it).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mailto support (for gmail etc). Don't know if possible, but would be nice to have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selection Mailing. Just let me select and mail some html.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Handle pdfs&lt;/strong&gt; better. By default chrome redirects to Safari for pdfs. After changing Chrome to default, it does handle pdfs fine, but I miss the &quot;Open In iBooks&quot; link. Don't see this happening though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Webintents&lt;/strong&gt; support would be nice to have (via something other than chrome Webstore, I Guess)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CloudPrint&lt;/strong&gt; support. I don't use this, but I am assuming there are people who do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FullScreen&lt;/strong&gt; support of some sort. Safari in iOS 6 is bringing this much asked for feature, so there are people who would love to have this. Chrome's faster tab switching should help it out with some of the Full Screen issues. (&lt;strong&gt;Edit&lt;/strong&gt;: This is available via a three finger tap if you install &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idownloadblog.com/2012/07/01/chromizer/&quot;&gt;Chromizer&lt;/a&gt; from Cydia's ModMyi repo). Chromizer also forces the iPhone style tab switching on the iPad as a side-effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There is also a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.idownloadblog.com/2012/07/01/chromeurl/&quot;&gt;ChromeURL&lt;/a&gt; tweak available for Jailbroken devices that changes the keyboard layout to the the one used for address bar in Safari (So called tld keyboard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one called &lt;a href=&quot;http://modmyi.com/content/8108-chromecustomization-adds-some-new-stuff-google-chrome.html&quot;&gt;ChromeCustomizer&lt;/a&gt; offers the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add one bookmarklet to the settings menu. I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;http://readable.tastefulwords.com/&quot;&gt;Readable&lt;/a&gt; at present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rpetrich/ChromeCustomizer/issues/1&quot;&gt;broken&lt;/a&gt; fullscreen implementation (maybe it is clashing with Chromizer) via the Menu. I prefer Chromizer's 3 finger tap for fullscreen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds a Find in Page feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds some filtering for ads/tracking websites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adds an option to change Chrome tab switching mode (iPhone vs iPad).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.addictivetips.com/ios/great-cydia-tweaks-for-chrome-iphone-ipad/&quot;&gt;this blog post&lt;/a&gt; for some more tweaks available on cydia.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Akira - Winning entry to the Adobe Express Apps Contest</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/05/23/phonegap-blog-post/"/>
   <updated>2012-05-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/05/23/phonegap-blog-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the obligatory blog post that comes along with winning the Adobe Express Apps Contest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Contest Rules&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest rules asked you to develop a mobile application, using Adobe Phonegap and related technologies(read Dreamweaver) in a time frame of hardly 18 hours. This duration was assuming that one does no sleep, which I did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem statement for the application was to create a mobile application for a SUV car manufacturer. The application had to be socially engaging and &lt;em&gt;use the hardware capabilities offered by the device&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Our Interpretation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started with the problem statement as the complete guide for our application and ought bottom up for an application that would be the least and best amount of work to create an app that fulfils the app requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started off with a few wireframes, and features thrown around. At the end of the one hour mark, we had our feature list down to :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owners can share pics of their cars. We wanted the application to be for the owners of the cars, which brings in a lot of additional data. Pic sharing was the most logical thing to do. We were thinking something like an Instagram Community where everybody posts pics about where they have been, their rigs and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mileage meter. This was a slight gamification of the GPS data that we get. At the start of every journey/trip, you could mark it as such in the app, and we would record your position every 5 minutes. At the end of the trip, you could mark your ending point and see how much you travelled. Also important was the fact that we decided to show a number corresponding to every application user, showing how many miles he/she has travelled so far. Seeing that the next guy has travelled only so and so more miles than you may lead you to travel more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maps, obviously. A map for all the previous journeys that you have taken.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Work&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried to start with JQ.Mobi, which is an alternative to Jquery Mobile, but could not justify it, and switched to JQuery Mobile as it offered better  integration with Dreamweaver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic application layout was done using a mix of JQuery Mobile and some custom css. I came across a very good service called Build Phonegap, that allows you to compile your Phonegap application online to different platforms. We started with basing our application on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/phonegap/phonegap-start&quot;&gt;Phonegap Starter App on GitHub&lt;/a&gt; which was quite good. The examples directory in the phonegap download is what we ended up using, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit&lt;/em&gt;: After working a lot more in mobile development, I have come to see a lot more frameworks, and find JQTouch to be quite the minimalist do-one-thing-well plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most difficult part was to get the application to compile for iOS, without paying the Apple Developer Licence. Since, I could not see myself selling iOS apps anytime soon in the Apple App Store, I was stuck with a jailbroken iPad + iPod Touch, and had to figure out out to compile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps, which took me a lot of time to find on the internet, include :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install the XCode and the Adobe Phonegap toolkit. I downloaded the latest version, 4.2 for xcode, which makes the process a bit easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n1ZDMmwYHdE&quot;&gt;this youtube video&lt;/a&gt; to allow xcode to compile your application without Code Signing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a corvora application in xcode and follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.phonegap.com/w/page/52010495/Getting%20Started%20with%20PhoneGap-Cordova%20and%20Xcode%204&quot;&gt;these instructions&lt;/a&gt; to add the www folder to the application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compile. If you have an iDevice connected, you should be able to compile and install your application in a single step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You may need to change your application configuration to &quot;Do not code sign&quot; for this to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting all the above steps to work for the first time, on a borrowed MacBook Pro was a lot of work, for a mac noob like me. But at the end, getting to see the application getting launched on multiple devices and looking equally good was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the time was spent on getting the application features to work, while fighting off sleep. The end result was a still-incomplete application , which ran on multiple devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Blackberry&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, we were not able to run the app on the only Blackberry Phone that we had as Phonegap only supports Blackberry 5 as of now, while our phone had been upgraded to 6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our winning strategy from the start had been to dazzle the judges with an application running across multiple devices, and working equally good. We were pretty sure that none of the other contestants would put in so much effort to get it to run on non-android devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Backend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote the application backend in PHP limonade, a framework that i am quite used to. The concept was to give out a rest api to the application to use to Authenticate users and carry out backend tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Code&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is obviously messy, as a result of being hacked in on a single 18 hour marathon. You may be able to get a few good ideas from the implementations, though. The entire code is available at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/akira&quot;&gt;akira&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/akira-backend&quot;&gt;akira-backend&lt;/a&gt; repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Thoughts on Phonegap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My second slide in the presentation I did for the contest(made on Keynote on the Ipad, while walking to the contest room) says proudly &quot;Phonegap is awesome&quot;. And i seriously mean that. I've got started in the world of mobile development, while not having to worry about cross browser compatibility issues, and the like. I can do stuff easily using the already existing technologies that I know and love. There are a ton of excellent Phonegap plugins out there, and many more being written right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really impressed with what a web developer could do with Phonegap, and its ease of use. The Adobe Developers promised me that the integration would be far better in Dreamweaver 6, which I might just try. Although, it was far easier for me to compile and install the application on an android phone, so I hardly used the emulator which I took the pains to install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Expectations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I'd really love, though is a Phonegap simulator. Instead of having to install an android emulator, what if Dreamweaver comes with a Phonegap simulator. Since Phonegap is all javascript, it should be trivial to create basic UIs that look and feel like the native interface of the OS chosen. I would still have to do final tests on the emulator, which i believe are worthless, compared to running it on actual devices. My point is, installing the android emulator and getting the app to run in a emulator is really no big deal, but turns out be a huge time consuming step. For interested web developers, this could be skipped pretty easily, if only Phonegap had its own simulator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all just theory, as you'd have to install the complete Android and ios sdk to compile it for your device, anyway. But it would be a welcome step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Presentation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentation was made as a string of screenshots developing the application, so its not really much help. But here it is anyway. &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/u/captn3m0/p/akira-presentation&quot;&gt;View Original&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script async class=&quot;speakerdeck-embed&quot; data-id=&quot;4f6effee933f08002201ea60&quot; data-ratio=&quot;1.3333333333333333&quot; src=&quot;//speakerdeck.com/assets/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;h1&gt;Prize&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I won a PS3. Yay!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any problems with the code, or the process, you can contact me at my &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;about page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sympathy: My vision of a code editor</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/05/20/sympathy-editor/"/>
   <updated>2012-05-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/05/20/sympathy-editor</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info&quot;&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: I have worked on an editor protype along the lines of this blog post. The result is called &lt;a href=&quot;/sympathy/&quot;&gt;Sympathy Editor&lt;/a&gt;. Please check it out.
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I've used more than a dozen of editors for mainly two purposes: coding, and writing text. The most liked and used among them would be [Notepad++][http://notepadplusplus.org/] and [Geany][http://geany.org/]. I'm also a vim user, and primarily a web developer. I've always liked simple tools that do one thing well, as per the unix philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The era of WYSIWYG editors in web development is long past. I'm yet to hear someone suggest Dreamweaver as a serious editor. If you were to go out in the Rails world, you'd mostly be met by vim/emacs/textmate fans. As a linux user, I use geany for most of my editing work, including blog posts, like this one (Markdown is hands down, the best thing to happen to word-processing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Browser meet Editor meet Terminal&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a few attempts at creating code editors (I don't like the term IDE) powered by the gecko engine some time back. None of them materialized to anything special. Today, a normal workflow for me involves 3 open applications - a browser (chromium), a terminal window, and a text-editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I'd alt-tab all the way to hell on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this stage, almost everyone will tell me, there is &lt;em&gt;no problem&lt;/em&gt; with this workflow. This &lt;em&gt;is exactly how it is supposed to work&lt;/em&gt;. But we are not in the 1990s when browsers were just another application. At any given time, I usually have multiple stackoverflow tabs open in the browser pertaining to the code I am writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand we have a terminal, which I usually use to run builds, compile, and do version control stuff. No amount of integrated IDE magic will make me move away from the beloved command line (as it should be).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest solution is to get a second monitor. And yes, I love using dual monitors. But I'm still not satisfied. I want something more. I have 3 core applications, but using 3 monitors is an extremely costly venture. So I'm stuck to running a text editor, and alt tabbing my way between Chromium and Gnome Terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Cloud IDEs&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the solutions that keeps popping up are the almighty cloud based IDEs (like c9.io), which I really like. But the experience is sub-par at best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another cool project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Gozala/sky-edit&quot;&gt;sky-edit&lt;/a&gt; involves an extension in mozilla, which enables one to edit any text file in the browser itself, by pointing it to &quot;edit:&quot; urls. This is closer to what my ultimate aim is: &quot;text editor in a browser, editing local files&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Workflow&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I'd want my workflow to be is point my browser to a text file, edit it in place, change the tab to the live site, and then refresh. Once I realize I have to restart apache, I'd just change my tab to the terminal one, and do my cli stuff there itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Shortcuts:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrl+T: New browser tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrl+E: New editor tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrl+Y: New Terminal tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrl+S: Save a file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;All &lt;code&gt;file://&lt;/code&gt; urls are browsable as usual, and all text files become editable. Just think of all the possibilities. As long as it uses plain old javascript/css, it could re-use most of the editing part from the excellent ace project. Even codemirror would work brilliantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best part is that it is still a complete browser. Meaning you get to use all your bookmarks, bookmarklets, plugins, and fancy stuff that you expect in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just think of the possibilities! Since this is just another browser, you can build extensions that target edit windows. Meaning an extension could add support for auto-completion very easily. And repeat for inline documentation browsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A build shortcut could probably be used to switch to a running version of the website in some way. What about other stuff? Like spell-checking? Browsers support that. Even dictation would probably work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And markdown editing! Hell yeah!. Edit it all in your browser itself, while keeping github open in another tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Start&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a simple propsal of sorts, to get a few recommendations about how this should proceed. I asked a similar question on the askubuntu forums, which made me realize what the real problems were. I'm trying to build chromium and get something off the ground. The project is tentatively titled &lt;code&gt;sympathy&lt;/code&gt; and has zero code as of now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to earlier write something similar in python, but realized that I could not build an awesome feature complete text-editor by myself. Which made me shift to forking something like geany. I then realized that getting the webview in geany to be feature-complete as a browser would be again heavily demanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest path out is to build the editor in the browser. Why? Because there has already been a lot of work done in this direction, including ace, bespin, codemirror and lots of other editors. Embedding the terminal is another problem, which will be harder to solve in the browser, but I'm willing to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, my plan is to fork chromium, and work on adding support for text-file editing in the browser. There are a few questions I'd like to answer over time, such as should the browser be stripped? Chromium is a heavy project, and includes some complex features baked right in, which are definately not needed in a text-editor. For instance &quot;Cloud Print&quot;, &quot;Chrome Sync&quot; etc. But at the same time, there is a reason to keep it in as well. I'd like to use this as my primary browser, using all the extensions, bookmarks, and sync features it offers me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds interesting? I've got no idea on how to approach this. Help me out. If you do not like facebook comments, please discuss this on Hacker News, or feel free to drop me a mail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did try my best on developing such a thing, and the end result (still far from finished) is &lt;a href=&quot;/sympathy/&quot;&gt;Sympathy Editor&lt;/a&gt;. Try out the beta. Hopefully you will like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Design of CaptNemo.in</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/03/31/new-design-captnemo-in/"/>
   <updated>2012-03-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/03/31/new-design-captnemo-in</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I did a redesign of the blog. The main goals for the redesign were to reach a
clean, readable layout, which I feel I've accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe frameborder='0' height='540' width='100%' src='http://min.us/mbneXkYyXF/3e'&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Old Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was plain old bootstrap, except for the hover effect on the
photograph. I've also removed the old &quot;Related Posts&quot; feature, which I felt was
not at all useful. In the old homepage, the list of articles was earlier presented as a list (&amp;lt;li&gt;), while it is now slightly better. The topbar has also been removed, instead focussing on a far better sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;New Stuff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted a &lt;em&gt;clean design&lt;/em&gt; more than anything. So instead of the sharebox being persistent on every device, I decided to hide it on lower resolutions. It currently hides if the screen width &amp;lt; 1100px, so unless you are on a widescreen resolution monitor and using your browser on fullscreen, you won't see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsive design via bootstrap allows you to easily support mobile devices. The left sidebar is stacked, so that even mobile devices have no problem with the layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd describe the design as &lt;em&gt;clean, minimal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earlier design was using Bootstrap 1.3, and I've upgraded to 2.0.2 now.
I've used the new version before, but with zero changes using
&lt;a href=&quot;http://bootswatch.com/&quot;&gt;bootswatch&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;/codechef/&quot;&gt;a few other places&lt;/a&gt;. But
this time, I decided to tweak bootstrap for my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did away with the navigation bar, and changed the default fonts. The site
does not feel like a stock bootstrap site any longer. The major contribution
from bootstrap, was in fact the grid system, and the responsiveness, which
really helped me get it done quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Typography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fonts used are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Ubuntu&quot;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; for the content, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts/specimen/Gentium+Book+Basic&quot;&gt;Gentium Book
Basic&lt;/a&gt; for the
headings. I'm using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/webfonts&quot;&gt;Google Web Fonts
Directory&lt;/a&gt; for the fonts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm only loading the italicized version of Gentium as I've chosen to display
all headings (h1-h6) as italics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What can we learn from Hollywood</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/03/22/hollywood-what-can-we-learn/"/>
   <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/03/22/hollywood-what-can-we-learn</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There is Lot of buzz in the startup industry regarding the killing of Hollywood. However, before we do that (Amen), there is something that I wish to learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how much we shout at their broken distribution model, there is one thing that I deeply admire about hollywood. It gets shit done. On time. Again and again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this important? Because it is One of the largest industries I see around that stick to deadlines on a regular basis. This is something deeply missing in the tech world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the trailers of a movie tell me that it will be out in summers, I know I can keep a block reserved for when it will come out. Quite unlike Microsoft, which may push back its release dates as often as it wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I thought the Tech industry was done with this deadline bullshit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I too despise deadlines and can't wait for them to get away, but this article is about something else. This is much more about the undying spirit of Hollywood to release stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So each time you are facing feature creep, and it looks like it will never ship, just look at Hollywood and get it done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Planet IITR Update</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/03/13/planet-iitr-update/"/>
   <updated>2012-03-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/03/13/planet-iitr-update</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I was just going through my old blog posts, and saw the &lt;a href=&quot;http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/07/09/announcing-planet-iitr/&quot;&gt;Planet IITR Update&lt;/a&gt;, which I created out of a need for people to be able to find blogs from other people in IITR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since no one has ever submitted a single link to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr&quot;&gt;planet&lt;/a&gt; , I just thought, why shouldn't I just crawl all my Facebook friends from IIT-R, and check their website URLs. The Facebook part took ~20 minutes (getting list of users from my 2 friendlists, followed by getting the website url for each of those friends). After that came the link checking part, which tool ~15-20 minutes as well. A list of all the websites (very few people fill up that that field on fb) I found during the search is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hastebin.com/quhexokere.dos&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (just 39).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After updating the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr&quot;&gt;planet&lt;/a&gt;, I had to update the spreadsheet as well. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr/subscriptions&quot;&gt;here's a list of the blogs&lt;/a&gt;, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.clipboard.com/embed/LQo5klMbO4eleZdgi28bUFHcXl7cS-ctHmPe?widthAdjust=0&amp;heightAdjust=0&amp;showBorder=0&amp;footerOn=false&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;3000&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In case someone is interested in taking over maintenance (meaning link curation) for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr&quot;&gt;Planet&lt;/a&gt;, please contact me at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x61;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#x74;&amp;#111;&amp;#58;&amp;#x63;&amp;#97;&amp;#112;&amp;#x74;&amp;#46;&amp;#110;&amp;#x33;&amp;#109;&amp;#48;&amp;#64;&amp;#103;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x61;&amp;#105;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x2e;&amp;#x63;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;&amp;#99;&amp;#x61;&amp;#x70;&amp;#116;&amp;#46;&amp;#110;&amp;#x33;&amp;#109;&amp;#48;&amp;#x40;&amp;#x67;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#x69;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#x63;&amp;#111;&amp;#x6d;&lt;/a&gt;, and I'll be glad to share the authentication details with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link to Planet : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr&quot;&gt;Planet IIT-R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you were wondering what this planet stuff is all about, it allows one to add a single curated feed to one's feed reader and get all updates via that. So planet iitr is a curated collection of blogs pertaining to IIT-R.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why you should learn HTTP?</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/03/05/why-learn-http/"/>
   <updated>2012-03-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/03/05/why-learn-http</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I see people learning RoR, PHP, Django, with a single intent: getting their own website. Of course, it is the million dollar idea that will blow everyone away, as always. But what I find fascinating is that too many upcoming web developers are testing the waters with opinionated coding frameworks. The entry barrier for software development has been lowered exponentially in the last decade, leading to a slew of web frameworks, tutorials, and screencasts. Today is arguably the best time to be involved in software development. Lots of people are learning to code their first web-site with rails, or django. There are lots of benifits with this approach: as a beginner, you are kept isolate from all the complexities, and can focus more easily on your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it also leads to shallow learning. You could have written a dozen sinatra apps, and still not understand how it all works. And as it stands, it is not essential to learn it. You can easily develop entire websites thinking only in terms of urls, hyperlinks, routes and controllers. This is all good for starting up, when you don't wanna deal with the complexity of it all, but I'd expect any competent web-developer to understand HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, HTTP is the foundation for all of web. It is how the internet tubes work. Learning HTTP is uncovering the hidden layer behind your browser. It is understanding how cookies, and sessions work in PHP; how xsrf attacks happen and mitigating against them; the magic that rails does when it creates objects from the submitted form parameters transparently for you. And the best part is that its not all that difficult to learn at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=2724488&quot;&gt;lot of debate concerning REST recently&lt;/a&gt;. I don't claim to understand REST fully. I'm yet to meet someone who does. But I can comfortably build RESTish APIs, and consume them with ease without breaking a sweat. And smile at the fact that its all just HTTP. You cannot move to REST, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HATEOAS&quot;&gt;HATEOAS&lt;/a&gt; unless you are comfortable with HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you are a beginner in web-development, here's my advice to you: Understand HTTP. A few pointers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781565925090.do&quot; title=&quot;HTTP: The Definitive Guide&quot;&gt;a good&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.oreilly.com/product/9781565928626.do&quot; title=&quot;HTTP Pocket Reference&quot;&gt;book&lt;/a&gt; on HTTP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616.html&quot;&gt;HTTP RFC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Computer_Networks/HTTP#HTTP&quot;&gt;Wikibooks&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Http&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; entries on HTTP are quite good.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the network tab in Webkit Inspector/Firebug. And understand each of the damn headers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start using &lt;code&gt;curl -i&lt;/code&gt;, if you don't already&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Above all, be curious&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Question the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Making post requests with 'request' module in node.js</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/02/22/make-post-request-with-requests-node.js/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/02/22/make-post-request-with-requests-node.js</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Was stuck at this for quite some time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;postData&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;};&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;request&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;({&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;uri&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://example.com/test&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;headers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;content-type&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;application/x-www-form-urlencoded&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;querystring&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;stringify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;postData&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;},&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;body&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;res&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;statusCode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This will make a post request to &lt;code&gt;http://example.com/test&lt;/code&gt; with the querystring parameters in postData. Meaning if you are using PHP, you can see the variables in &lt;code&gt;$_POST&lt;/code&gt; instead of parsing request body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/1360979&quot;&gt;https://gist.github.com/1360979&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mikeal/request&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mikeal/request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The only way I can work any longer</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/02/18/the-only-way-i-can-work/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-18T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/02/18/the-only-way-i-can-work</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being a good programmer is 3% talent and 97% not getting distracted by the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, a frank admission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I procastinate.&lt;br/&gt;
A lot.&lt;br/&gt;
Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For every second I spend in front of my computer, trying to get some work done, there is a continous struggle going on between my &quot;work&quot; and &quot;play&quot; side of things. Unfortunately, the &quot;play&quot; side seems to be winning. &lt;strong&gt;A lot&lt;/strong&gt;. So I decided to wage a war against it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my arsenal of tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leftnode/get-shit-done&quot;&gt;get-shit-done&lt;/a&gt; - Script blocks all access to various sites(FB,reddit etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://support.google.com/chrome/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=142059&quot;&gt;Chrome Profiles&lt;/a&gt; - One of my profiles is called &quot;get-shit-done&quot;. It features my development extensions, apps, bookmarks, and nothing else. It is plain vanilla Chromium with no puffy unicorns luring me to check my Facebook Notifications.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/f7B9C.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome Profiles&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music - I find Youtube a surprising good source of music discovery. I listen to almost everything. Recently, I've started to listen to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OB3wgiaOOvA&quot;&gt;Ludovico Einaudi&lt;/a&gt;. You may also like &lt;a href=&quot;http://musicforprogramming.net/&quot;&gt;http://musicforprogramming.net/&lt;/a&gt; in this regard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal Tabs - I close a tab as soon as I'm done with it. This leads to ~3-5 tabs in my &quot;get-shit-done&quot; setup. A lesser number of tabs usually means a limit on the number of distracting links. Even Stackoverflow doesn't help in this regard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The get-shit-done profile even has settings to clear cache at closings. This leads to me being signed out of everything. Including GMail, Facebook, SO, and everything else. In this mode, I login to something, if it is essential to the work at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.readitlater.com/&quot;&gt;Read It Later&lt;/a&gt; - I've setup all &lt;a href=&quot;http://hckrnews.com&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; feeds above 20 points to be saved automatically to my Read It Later account, which I can easily consume on my iPad at my leisure. However, I find myself itching to browse hckrnews every 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you find yourself browsing facebook, reddit, youtube, hacker news, or reading blog posts on productivity, I urge you strongly to try this out. Defeating procastination is not easy. And its never a win-or-lose battle. What are your thoughts? How do you stop yourself from getting lost on the internetz? Tell me in comments.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Things I love about Github</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/02/02/on-github/"/>
   <updated>2012-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/02/02/on-github</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A slide from GitHub's famous &quot;How Github uses Github to build Github talk&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4e79b461c9bdcb003f00331d.js?slide=10&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In their recent version of the talk at RubyConf 2011, they changed the slide slightly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://dl.dropbox.com/u/1766113/vlcsnap-2012-02-01-16h24m32s103.png&quot; alt=&quot;No pings&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It now reads, &quot;No Pings&quot; instead of &quot;No Managers&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not nitpicking, just paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven't seen the talk (or just saw the slideshow), you should go and watch the talk (31 mins) &lt;a href=&quot;http://confreaks.com/videos/706-rubyconf2011-how-github-uses-github-to-build-github&quot;&gt;Right Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Choose Between Facebook Groups and Pages</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2012/01/26/facebook-choose-group-vs-page/"/>
   <updated>2012-01-26T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2012/01/26/facebook-choose-group-vs-page</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know how many times I've said this, but the best way of creating a multi-user discussion platform is to create a facebook page. A little guidelines on what you should use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a group when you really need it (for &lt;100 people) and when you want to have close knit discussions. (People get notifications for each post on the group) -&gt; Leads to spamming&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never create a fake profile for an organization/event/celebrity/anything that is not you. Creating fake profiles is actually against Facebook's TOS, and can lead to account discontinuation. Plus the barrier of friending a person (instead of &quot;liking it) is higher enough to lead to lesser number of followers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a Facebook Page for every other case. If you are a brand/news/startup/organization (public facing). This is usually the best choice, and it gives you the best outreach of all. (Especially if you want to reach out to People).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In short, just create a Page, unless you know what you are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google, Fix your Google+ API</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/12/06/google-plus-api-fixit/"/>
   <updated>2011-12-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/12/06/google-plus-api-fixit</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Google,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please release the Google+ write API as well. In case you've forgotten, its been 6 months since you launched. I've got stuff I wanna post, stuff I wanna develop. Please keep to your promises, and don't make me quote Steve Yegge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, while you are at it, please fix &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/google-plus-platform/issues/detail?id=83&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;/a&gt; and make the list of +1d url's available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,
A frustrated developer and Google+ user.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Someone jailbreak my iPad</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/12/05/someone-jailbreak-my-ipad/"/>
   <updated>2011-12-05T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/12/05/someone-jailbreak-my-ipad</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a rant, mainly targeted at Apple. If you are a Apple fanboi, just &lt;a href=&quot;daringfireball.net&quot;&gt;go&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/&quot;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, and quickly. I can't take another minute of this iTunes. It refuses to properly sync songs, does not update my songs tag info, unless I play them individually, and to top it all, my iPad gives out incorrect usage information about my apps. I tried adding them up, and it seems the total is way off. And since everything in thr Apple land lives happily inside the propertiery Apple File System, I cannot even check it realiabily. And don't even get me started on the the application transfers. The file sharing system is so bad in iOS that almost evey other app comes built in with a wi-fi or ftp server. When alomst mevery app that deals with files starts ro do that, there is something definately wrong with your file system approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why doesn't my itunes recognize any video files at all. I was given a warning about needing QuickTime, and I installed it, but it still refuses to play them in iTunes, and doesn't even give me an error string to hold on to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, iTunes go back to the bloatware land that you came from. I'll try my luck with something else from now on. And only if someone could give me the specs for the arcane plist format, I might write a PC version of the iBooks app. And calibre needs to fix up its pdf to epub approach. Inline styles are not used anymore, doesn't it know already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A few days later...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a few more days with my iPad, I have developed a love/hate relationship wit it. I hate the ugly sync process, which still refuses to sync videos, telling me I have to delete everything to start sync. I love it for its ease of use, awesome touch, and aesthetics. I hate it for its lack of support, oepn sync protocols, and most of all Apple's close mindedness regarding unsigned binaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously Apple, if tablets are the computer of the future, treat them as auch. Let me treat it as a fully functional comouter, which lets me run whatever I want, with whatever privileges I want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Microsoft had tried to create such a walled garden of apps in Windows, would it have been so successful? Granted, people would love running apps from Windows 8 Marketplace, if only because it would keep their software updated. But Windows at least has a choice,to allow me to download a tiny binary from a small Windows Developer who does not want to pay MS just to let people use his/her apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An appstore is an excellent idea, executed brilliantly by Apple, but please follow MS and give us an official way to do whatever the hell I want to do with my iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A few weeks later...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really hate my iPad now, especially once I realise that my cheap Nokia cell phone has tether support, while my iPad does not.  To do any task that may require you access to a normal file system, such as cloning a repository from github, or editing an document anywhere is impossible in the device. I love playing games on it, though, but it seems like a really costly device to play games and read books on. Get the Fire at less than half the price, and root it to install cyanogen mod (which will soon be available for the Fire).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I wonder if Indian carriers would have installed Carrier IQ on an iPad (which comes without a SIM card). I'll find out as soon as I can root it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my friends gave a very serious comment on the iPad : &quot;It seems as if you have rented the device from Apple, rather than bought it&quot;. And I've come to realise that its a reflection of the sad state that the electronics manufacturing industry is in today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;A few more weeks later :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I jailbroke my iPad :)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Further links :&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;Jailbreakingisnotacrime.org&quot;&gt;Jailbreaking Is Not A Crime&lt;/a&gt; - Sign the petition&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5863640&quot;&gt;Kindle fire unroots itself&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2011/12/16/2642039/&quot;&gt;Fire doesnt allow you to visit android marketplace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/5863895/&quot;&gt;Carrier IQ controversy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gsmarena.com/nokia_x2_01-3610.php&quot;&gt;Nokia dumb phone features&lt;/a&gt; - X2-01&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How &lt;a href=&quot;http://cydiablog.com/category/jailbreak/&quot;&gt;I Jailbroke my iPad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Experience with the Deloitte Cyber Collegiate Threat Competition (2011)</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/11/20/cctc-blog/"/>
   <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/11/20/cctc-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently was part of a team at IIT-Roorkee that won the Deloitte Cyber Collegiate Threat Competition. It was a competition modeled after The Deloitte sponsored CCDC in the US. The event will be organized in the subsequent years as well, and hence this blog post will summarize my experience so as to help any future participants. Moreover, the organizing team has guaranteed us that the competition will be altered significantly in the coming years. This was the first year that this event was organized, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I'll go into the contest round by round, so beginning with Round 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Round 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deloitte came to our campus, with little promotion about the event. A presentation was given on the current scenario of Cyber Threat, particularly with respect to India. Free swag was awarded to people who asked some good questions, or answered some as well. After the presentation, a quiz was goven out, consisting mainly of questions about Web Application Security. A few of the questions asked to write down code to circumvent a particular issue (like SQL Injection). But it was mostly about stuff that every security conscious Web Developer would know about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the quiz, they selected the top 9 candidates, and asked us to form teams. Make sure that you attend the quiz with your friends, as we definitely had an edge by knowing everyone in our team before the event. The number of teams varied from campus to campus. But if you perform decent enough, you will be selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Round 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of the teams were given a VM Image, and we were asked to hack into it. We were not allowed to exploit vulnerabilities in the guest OS, or things like VMWare, or try to boot into the image with another OS, but other than that everything went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VM had a library application, with several vulnerabilities. A challenge sheet was mailed to us, and we were expected to finish as many challenges as we could. Any further vulnerabilities not mentioned in the challenge could also be mentioned, but theywere only to be used in the case of a tie with another team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time duration for Round 2 was 15 days and we were supposed to submit our reports by then. We were able to complete most of the challenges after we found a blind sql injection vulnerablity. Further, we were able to get a copy of the obsfucated PHP code, which we converted to simpler versions easily enough. We had no way to make use of the code, but it did help us in identifying possible files and entry routes for vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a good score in round 2, try to attack every point in the application. In our case, some of them were too stupid to be used in a real case scenario. For instance, we had password hashes appearing in images. Pour through the javascript code, and search like hell. Stuff like w3af might help you, but since its a limited application only, it is often easier to just track the application flow. We did try kernel level exploites, but the VM was fully patched and up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Round 3&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Round 3 was organized at Hyderabad and was a head on hack everything contest. We were handed 3 virtual machines, with lots of vulnerable services. We had to keep those services running, which were periodically pinged by a scorebot. Scores were awarded in three categories : attack, defense, and flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attack points were earned upon getting a shell on any of the other team's servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flag points of awardedon the basis of getting access to secrets stored inside the other team's servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense points were earned on the basis of status of your own service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The network architecture was 3 tiered. A single central router routed requests to a team's router, which was then connected to an individual team switch. A switch was connected to the host VM, and the attack machines. Two different subnets were created for attack and defense in each team's router. All uVMs were present in the attack subnets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 consisted mostly of us learning about the network and trying to gain access into the other systems. All the services were highly vulnerable, and as a result, we had to patch that vulnerability in our own servers before we attacked anyone with it. DoS attacks started late in theday, but were ever present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The VMs handed t us included a Windows Server 2003, a debian, and an Ubuntu. Only open source/freeware tools were allowed, and we used lots of stuff including :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backtrack for almost everything since attack laptops given to us had Windows installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LOIC for DoS attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wireshark for packet analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snort for intrusion detection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NMap for scanning services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metasploit for trying out exploits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cain and Abel for miscellaneous stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 2 involves lots of pwning,and a surprise twist. All VMs for day 1 had been reset to their current state, and we had to do patch them all over again in first fifteen minutes of the session. Other than that, the increase in traffic was exponential. All our machines were scanned tonell. DoS attacks became normal, and the epic moment of the day was during the last session when we had our router pwned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pics from the Event are at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.2204003219759.2107008.1237711792&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kudos to the Deloitte Team for organizing such a brilliant contest. We had lots of fun. They have assured us that next year it will be even bigger and better. And that the format will be entirely Different. Ext hear so this blog post might not be as helping as you may have thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Github +1 URLs</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/10/17/github-projects-to-follow/"/>
   <updated>2011-10-17T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/10/17/github-projects-to-follow</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was working on the Google +1 Listing API (undocumented). So here's a list of my current +1 urls on github.com. Most of the projects pertain to web-designing. I'll update this list automatically every week or so, provided I remember to/set a cron job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tbody id=&quot;urls&quot;&gt;
    &lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jayferd/color.js&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/jayferd/color.js&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/jayferd/color.js&quot;&gt;jayferd/color.js - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/jayferd/color.js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;color.js - The missing color library&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/typicaljoe/taffydb&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/typicaljoe/taffydb&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/typicaljoe/taffydb&quot;&gt;typicaljoe/taffydb - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/typicaljoe/taffydb&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;taffydb - TaffyDB - an open source JavaScript Database for your browser&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/antirez/lamernews&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/antirez/lamernews&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/antirez/lamernews&quot;&gt;antirez/lamernews - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/antirez/lamernews&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;lamernews - Lamer News -- an HN style social news site written in Ruby/Sinatra/Redis/JQuery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/felixge/node-mysql/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/felixge/node-mysql/&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/felixge/node-mysql/&quot;&gt;felixge/node-mysql - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/felixge/node-mysql/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;node-mysql - A pure node.js JavaScript Client implementing the MySql protocol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/daneden/animate.css&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/daneden/animate.css&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/daneden/animate.css&quot;&gt;daneden/animate.css - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/daneden/animate.css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;animate.css - A big ol' goody bag filled with CSS animations for WebKit, Firefox and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/javve/list&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/javve/list&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/javve/list&quot;&gt;javve/list - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/javve/list&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you want a 7 KB cross-browser native JavaScript that makes your plain HTML lists super flexible, searchable, sortable and filterable? Yea&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/azer/jekyll-social-activities&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/azer/jekyll-social-activities&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/azer/jekyll-social-activities&quot;&gt;azer/jekyll-social-activities - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/azer/jekyll-social-activities&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;jekyll-social-activities - a jekyll project template to list social network activities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/e1ven/Robohash&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/e1ven/Robohash&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/e1ven/Robohash&quot;&gt;e1ven/Robohash - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/e1ven/Robohash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Robohash - RoboHash.org&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/donpark/node-robohash&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/donpark/node-robohash&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/donpark/node-robohash&quot;&gt;donpark/node-robohash - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/donpark/node-robohash&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;node-robohash - node.js implementation of Robohash. It's neither complete nor render general SVG.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lg/marshmallow&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lg/marshmallow&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/lg/marshmallow&quot;&gt;lg/marshmallow - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/lg/marshmallow&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;marshmallow - An open source Campfire server&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tmcw/big&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tmcw/big&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/tmcw/big&quot;&gt;tmcw/big - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tmcw/big&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;big - presentations for busy messy hackers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/964-all-of-the-hooks&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/964-all-of-the-hooks&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/blog/964-all-of-the-hooks&quot;&gt;All of the Hooks - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/blog/964-all-of-the-hooks&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Service Hooks are available for more events (issues, pull requests, forks, etc).  Update them through the API!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/chromakode/karmabot&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/chromakode/karmabot&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/chromakode/karmabot&quot;&gt;chromakode/karmabot - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/chromakode/karmabot&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;karmabot - A highly extensible IRC karma+information bot written in Python.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/reddit/reddit/blob/master/r2/r2/controllers/buttons.py&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/reddit/reddit/blob/master/r2/r2/controllers/buttons.py&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/reddit/reddit/blob/master/r2/r2/controllers/buttons.py&quot;&gt;r2/r2/controllers/buttons.py at master from reddit/reddit - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/reddit/reddit/blob/master/r2/r2/controllers/buttons.py&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;the code that powers reddit.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/moserware/PHPSkills&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/moserware/PHPSkills&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/moserware/PHPSkills&quot;&gt;moserware/PHPSkills - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/moserware/PHPSkills&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;PHPSkills - An implementation of the TrueSkill algorithm in PHP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejitsu/docs&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejitsu/docs&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/nodejitsu/docs&quot;&gt;nodejitsu/docs - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/nodejitsu/docs&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;docs - Community powered rocket fuel for node.js&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fgnass.github.com/spin.js/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=http://fgnass.github.com/spin.js/assets/preview.jpg?v=1&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://fgnass.github.com/spin.js/&quot; title=&quot;http://fgnass.github.com/spin.js/&quot;&gt;spin.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://fgnass.github.com/spin.js/&quot;&gt;fgnass.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;An animated CSS activity indicator with VML fallback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blackberry.github.com/Alice/demos.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;./default_url.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://blackberry.github.com/Alice/demos.html&quot; title=&quot;http://blackberry.github.com/Alice/demos.html&quot;&gt;Alice.js Demos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://blackberry.github.com/Alice/demos.html&quot;&gt;blackberry.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alice.js Demos. Alice.js (A Lightweight Independent CSS Engine) is a micro JavaScript library focused on using hardware-accelerated capabili&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tcorral/Design-Patterns-in-Javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tcorral/Design-Patterns-in-Javascript&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/tcorral/Design-Patterns-in-Javascript&quot;&gt;tcorral/Design-Patterns-in-Javascript - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tcorral/Design-Patterns-in-Javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design-Patterns-in-Javascript - Based in examples on Head First Design Patterns&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/atduskgreg/srender&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/atduskgreg/srender&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/atduskgreg/srender&quot;&gt;atduskgreg/srender - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/atduskgreg/srender&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;srender - John Resig's Simple Javascript Templating turned into a jQuery Plugin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/functional-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/functional-javascript&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/functional-javascript&quot;&gt;mrdavidlaing/functional-javascript - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/functional-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;functional-javascript - A fun set of koans to teach you functional programming techniques in Javascript&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans&quot;&gt;mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mrdavidlaing/javascript-koans&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;javascript-koans - Koans to learn Javascript&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robrighter/current&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/robrighter/current&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/robrighter/current&quot;&gt;robrighter/current - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/robrighter/current&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;current - Node.js app for visualizing http requests on a lan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bcoe/endtable&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/bcoe/endtable&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/bcoe/endtable&quot;&gt;bcoe/endtable - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/bcoe/endtable&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;endtable - A ridiculously simple Object Mapper for Node running on top of CouchDB.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sproutcore/sproutcore&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/sproutcore/sproutcore&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/sproutcore/sproutcore&quot;&gt;sproutcore/sproutcore - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/sproutcore/sproutcore&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;sproutcore - JavaScript Application Framework - JS library only&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/tpope&quot;&gt;tpope's Profile - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;tpope (Tim Pope). You're not logged in! Login; Pricing &amp;amp; Signup. Name: Tim Pope. Website/Blog: http://tpo.pe/. Company: Waiting on t&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive&quot;&gt;tpope/vim-fugitive - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/tpope/vim-fugitive&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;vim-fugitive - fugitive.vim: a Git wrapper so awesome, it should be illegal&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/github/gitignore&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/github/gitignore&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/github/gitignore&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;/gitignore - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/github/gitignore&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A collection of useful .gitignore templates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://harvesthq.github.com/chosen/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;./default_url.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://harvesthq.github.com/chosen/&quot; title=&quot;http://harvesthq.github.com/chosen/&quot;&gt;Chosen - a JavaScript plugin for jQuery and Prototype - makes select boxes better&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://harvesthq.github.com/chosen/&quot;&gt;harvesthq.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Standard Select. Turns This. United States, United Kingdom, Afghanistan, Albania, Algeria, American Samoa, Andorra, Angola, Anguilla, Antarc&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/harvesthq/chosen&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/harvesthq/chosen&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/harvesthq/chosen&quot;&gt;harvesthq/chosen - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/harvesthq/chosen&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;chosen - Chosen is a library for making long, unwieldy select boxes more friendly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rthauby/Paige&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rthauby/Paige&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/rthauby/Paige&quot;&gt;rthauby/Paige - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/rthauby/Paige&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paige - Super simple project page generation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jashkenas.github.com/docco/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;./default_url.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://jashkenas.github.com/docco/&quot; title=&quot;http://jashkenas.github.com/docco/&quot;&gt;docco.coffee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://jashkenas.github.com/docco/&quot;&gt;jashkenas.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docco is a quick-and-dirty, hundred-line-long, literate-programming-style documentation generator. It produces HTML that displays your comme&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/LeaVerou/prefixfree&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/LeaVerou/prefixfree&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/LeaVerou/prefixfree&quot;&gt;LeaVerou/prefixfree - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/LeaVerou/prefixfree&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;prefixfree - Break free from prefix hell!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twitter/scala_school&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/twitter/scala_school&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/twitter/scala_school&quot;&gt;twitter/scala_school - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/twitter/scala_school&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;scala_school - Lessons in the Fundamentals of Scala&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arcturo/library&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/arcturo/library&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/arcturo/library&quot;&gt;arcturo/library - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/arcturo/library&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A library of free eBooks we're working on&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timcameronryan/cross-browser-selection&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/timcameronryan/cross-browser-selection&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/timcameronryan/cross-browser-selection&quot;&gt;timcameronryan/cross-browser-selection - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/timcameronryan/cross-browser-selection&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;cross-browser-selection - A tiny JavaScript DOM selection library for modern browsers and IE5-8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dodgeball.github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;./default_url.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://dodgeball.github.com/&quot; title=&quot;http://dodgeball.github.com/&quot;&gt;First Annual Octocat Dodgeball Invitational&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://dodgeball.github.com/&quot;&gt;dodgeball.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why? We were brainstorming in the office and decided we should throw balls at our enemies. But why stop at destroying our enemies with foam &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://coreh.github.com/nide/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/img/5d21241b64dc708fcbb701f68f72f41e9f1fadd6/687474703a2f2f73332e616d617a6f6e6177732e636f6d2f6769746875622f726962626f6e732f666f726b6d655f6c6566745f7265645f6161303030302e706e67&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://coreh.github.com/nide/&quot; title=&quot;http://coreh.github.com/nide/&quot;&gt;nide - Beautiful IDE for Node.JS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://coreh.github.com/nide/&quot;&gt;coreh.&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;nide. Beautiful IDE for Node.JS. nide is a web-based IDE for Node.js, designed with simplicity and ease-of-use in mind. The current version &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mikeal/request&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mikeal/request&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/mikeal/request&quot;&gt;mikeal/request - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/mikeal/request&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simplified HTTP request client.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/unconed/TermKit&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/unconed/TermKit&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/unconed/TermKit&quot;&gt;unconed/TermKit - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/unconed/TermKit&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;TermKit - Experimental Terminal platform built on WebKit + node.js. Currently only for Mac and Windows, though the prototype works 90% in an&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://usersinhell.com/dropbox-github-pricing/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=http://usersinhell.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/07/365x560xDropBoxGitHubPricing.png.pagespeed.ic.-eo24nEbnh.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot; style=&quot;width: 45px; height: 45px; &quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;http://usersinhell.com/dropbox-github-pricing/&quot; title=&quot;http://usersinhell.com/dropbox-github-pricing/&quot;&gt;If Dropbox Used &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;s Pricing Plan | Users in Hell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;http://usersinhell.com/dropbox-github-pricing/&quot;&gt;usersinhell.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Dropbox Used &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;'s Pricing Plan. What if Dropbox used &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;'s pricing model? Folders? Yes, folders. I have a lot of folders. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr userid=&quot;116290713924645527187&quot; style=&quot;display: table-row; &quot;&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img onload=&quot;img_load(this);&quot; onerror=&quot;img_error(this);&quot; src=&quot;http://images-pos-opensocial.googleusercontent.com/gadgets/proxy?url=https://a248.e.akamai.net/assets.github.com/images/modules/header/logov6.png&amp;amp;container=pos&amp;amp;resize_w=45&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;title&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;Secure source code hosting and collaborative development - &lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;link &quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;github&lt;/span&gt;.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;971406 people hosting over 2743662 git repositories. jQuery, reddit, Sparkle, curl, Ruby on Rails, node.js, ClickToFlash, Erlang/OTP, CakePH&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;List Of Watched Repositories from Github&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.clipboard.com/embed/LQztbTSJvWyI3zAaERcC6FnMUlAdDH56h8He?widthAdjust=0&amp;heightAdjust=0&amp;showBorder=0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;1561&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Must Use Web Applications</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/10/15/awesome-webapps/"/>
   <updated>2011-10-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/10/15/awesome-webapps</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of the applications that I would heavily recommend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://workflowy.com&quot;&gt;Workflowy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how Workflow describes itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;WorkFlowy is a simple, but powerful way to manage all the information in your life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's how others do it :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.clipboard.com/embed/LR-8z6u7uFeEcTNODs5_DeRtkifW8edCdOye?widthAdjust=0&amp;heightAdjust=0&amp;showBorder=0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;565&quot; height=&quot;381&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here's their introductory video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/CSmbnaPZVHE&quot; frameborder=&quot;1&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If that does not hook you, I don't know what will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://clipboard.com&quot;&gt;Clipboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clipboard is a content archiver tool that makes it quick, snappy, easy, and cool. It has got tons of features and is still in private beta. However, since Michael Arrington blogged about it, it has begun accepting larger number of invites. I've only started to use it, but it has been quite awesome till now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here's a demo from their help page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.clipboard.com/embed/LR-8xlAJpcz8vTxsbSluvzYbuTH9jgCZ_ZHe?widthAdjust=0&amp;heightAdjust=0&amp;showBorder=0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;691&quot; height=&quot;240&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My favorite feature is &lt;em&gt;embed&lt;/em&gt;. Everything I've embedded on this page is via clipboard, as a demo. You can clip tweets, pics, videos and what not and embed it on your blog easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ge.tt/&quot;&gt;Ge.tt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ge.tt is one of the many file sharing sites that seem to have cropped up in Web 2.0. Its USP is its simplicty, however don't be fooled by it. It has got lots of features as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/gett.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gett Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share URLs while your stuff is uploading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share without even logging in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drag and drop upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Versioning for file Uploads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share multiple files under a single upload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited Analytics (See number of Downloads)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So yes, its not as powerful as many others, but has got quite enough features to keep me busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://minus.com&quot;&gt;Minus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Minus is a simple image sharing service. It was amongst the first to offer Drag-And-Drop upload back before it was cool. Right now, it is trying to become the next flickr, allowing people to subscribe to each other. If you are someone who posts cool pics regularly, check this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/minus.png&quot; alt=&quot;Minus Home Page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary browser is Chromium, and here are some Chrome Applications that I use regularly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ejidjjhkpiempkbhmpbfngldlkglhimk?hc=hp-pr&amp;amp;hcp=pr2-2&quot;&gt;Offline GMail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/G7YSss4-ULNnV0NPYE3UDszmIAdeV8l3FWAqK0qy_s7LmCTiqG5JeRkl6pEXed2fCwhtoZEU=s400-h275-e365&quot; alt=&quot;Offline GMail Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Pros:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks cool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows multiple accounts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drafs facility&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Labels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not all the functionality of Online GMail&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Collaborative Editors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like collaborative editing, working together with people in real-time. Unfortunately, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wave.google.com&quot;&gt;biggest entrant&lt;/a&gt; fizzed out. However, there are still quite a lot of competitors left in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com&quot;&gt;Google Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to avoid Google Docs usually, as it is too much of a bloat for me. The integration with Google Chat is good, but sometimes all you need is a plain text editor. There is also an &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/apdfllckaahabafndbhieahigkjlhalf?hc=search&amp;amp;hcp=main&quot;&gt;Offline Google Docs&lt;/a&gt; application, although it does not allow one to edit documents. Also no presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://etherpad.com&quot;&gt;Etherpad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etherpad is quite good, as a plain text collaborative editor. I tend it to use it frequently, and it has some excellent features. It makes a thousand revisions of each of my posts, and allows me to play through them, and see who made wat change in real-time. All this, for free. Plus you get chat, and basic formatting (bold, italics, underline).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previously mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;http://workflowy.com&quot;&gt;workflowy&lt;/a&gt; keeps your lists in sync over time, so it is collaborative, though not in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, mention goes out to &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastehtml.com&quot;&gt;pastehtml&lt;/a&gt;, which does an excellent job. Its neither collaborative nor has sharing, but it had me hooked at &lt;em&gt;editable markdown&lt;/em&gt;. You can type in markdown, publish in html, and come back and edit your documents, as per your your heart's wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://grooveshark.com&quot;&gt;Grooveshark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I rarely listen to music online, but when I do, its either on Youtube or Grooveshark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/grooveshark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Grooveshark Screenshot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at this document, it seems that there are not many web-apps that I use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other applications that I regularly use, in no particular order:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://freedcampd.com&quot;&gt;FreedCamp&lt;/a&gt; - A free alternative to &lt;a href=&quot;http://basecamphq.com&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.issueburner.com/&quot;&gt;IssueBurner&lt;/a&gt; - Simple Issue Tracking via Email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.postary.com/&quot;&gt;Postary&lt;/a&gt; - A simple blogging platform. &quot;Write.Share.&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lastpass.com&quot;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt; - Password Manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'll probably add some Chrome Extensions later as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Blogging with Jekyll</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/09/19/jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2011-09-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/09/19/jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the past few years, there has been a revolution in the blogging scene. People have moved towards better hosting providers, better blogging tools, with automated, and delayed blogging becoming the norm. Posts are written months in advance, and proof-read dozens of times, before making it to the general public. &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogspot.com&quot;&gt;Blogspot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt;, Posterous, Texpaterrn are pretty much everything that most of the bloggers use. However, there have been some silent niche entries in this market. Static Site Generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Static Site Generators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static Site Generators are tools which you use to generate a static version of your site. Instead of using a dynamic scripting language (such as php), your tool takes in your markup &amp;amp; combines it with your blog posts to generate an html only version of your site. This version is then uploaded(for eg, via ftp) and is then visible as your blog. Most such tools are written in languages such as &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;python&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;node.js&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;erlang&lt;/code&gt;. The most commonly known are Jekyll, Hyde, nanoc, and webby. An excellent list is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://iwantmyname.com/blog/2011/02/list-static-website-generators.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Benifits of using Static Site Generators&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Markup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the most important part of using Jekyll is that it allows me to use &lt;code&gt;markdown&lt;/code&gt; as my writing syntax. Markdown is a markup language that is compiled to HTML. It is supposed to be a highly readable version of html. For instance it uses backticks(`) to write code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;`this` becomes &lt;code&gt;this&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you can use * to emphasize text(strong or emphasis). Link creation is not the horrible &amp;lt;a href=&amp;gt; that you remember, but the sleek looking [Link text](Link URL). Similarly it offers lots of other features. You can even specify alternative markup languages, such as textile in jekyll configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Ease Of Blogging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can write blog entries very easily. I've added markdown syntax bindings to &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;, my favorite editor, and geany has a markdown plugin as well. I am of the opinion that you should write text entries in a text-editor, not a textarea in a browser window. I used Windows Live Writer for quite some time and still believe that it is far ahead of anything else in the market. But the wpost format that it uses is propertiery, and as such stopped me from importing blog posts anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Revision Control&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revision Control, such as &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, works best with text-files. Since your blog entries are now just plain text files, you can easily store them under version control, easily reverting blotched commits, making branches, and merging errors. And in case you do not know it yet, &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; is awesome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Layout Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll allows you to define your layout using Liquid Templating. {{content}} translates to the variable content. Similarly you can iterate over blog posts, by using Liquid tags for &lt;code&gt;foreach&lt;/code&gt;. The best part is that this is all done before publishing your website, meaning that the final result is always just pure html. You can easily create static portions of your site (such as headers, footers, sidebars).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Getting Started With Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'll start with jekyll, since it is the most used one out there, and runs on github. It even powers this very blog. First, you must install jekyll. On an Ubuntu machine, &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install ruby rubygems &amp;amp;&amp;amp; gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt; should work. If you are working on development using Ruby, I'd recommend you to &lt;code&gt;rvm&lt;/code&gt;, instead of plain vanilla distro ruby installs. For windows folks, install Ruby, and the Devkit using RubyInstaller.org. After that run &lt;code&gt;gem install jekyll&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of preparing a site from scratch, we will instead be forking an existing site running on jekyll, and using it to model our own. This is partly to shield this tutorial from html/css/js which is irrelevant in this case. In this particular case, I will be using &lt;a href=&quot;http://captnemo.in&quot;&gt;my very own website&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/captn3m0/captn3m0.github.com&quot;&gt;Download the source code&lt;/a&gt; for my website from github and extract it somewhere. Next, you will have to delete all the content inside the &lt;em&gt;posts, projects, &lt;/em&gt;drafts, contact, &amp;amp; data directories as I do not give permission to you do use those in your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, create a file called &lt;code&gt;_posts/2011-month-date.md&lt;/code&gt; with the following format :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;code class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
---
title: Title Of Post
layout: post
---
The blog entry follows here in markdown. You can use *italic*, **bold**, [Link](http://google.com), #header1, ##header2 etc.

For more markdown details, visit its official page at http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax#autolink
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, open up the _layouts/ and edit default.html. You'd need basic html skills to replace my photo with your own, and change links to various places. After you are done, just &lt;code&gt;cd&lt;/code&gt; into the root directory of the site, and run &lt;code&gt;jekyll&lt;/code&gt;. Some output should confirm that the server ran successfully. Open up &lt;code&gt;http://localhost:4000&lt;/code&gt; in your browser, and you will see your web-site running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the hosting part. All of your current site is hosted in _site folder, so you can upload it anytime you want. Or, if you want, you can use github as your hosting provider. Just follow the instructions on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;pages.github.com&lt;/a&gt; and you should be be up and running in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tags: jekyll, blogging, editing, markdown, weblog-ifest 2011&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Six Months of Ubuntu</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/09/13/6-months-of-ubuntu/"/>
   <updated>2011-09-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/09/13/6-months-of-ubuntu</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I installed Ubuntu as my primary OS back sometime in February. Not that I'd not tried it earlier. In fact, I'd used a copy of Ubuntu 3 back in day. But this time around, Windows (from my dual boot) just gave up and died. The partition with Windows got heavily corrupted, lost lots of data, and ultimately I had to format it. And Ubuntu dragged through all that. And here I'm today, a veteran of 3 Ubuntu versions, starting with 10.10, and right now on the 11.10 beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have I learned ? That its better than Windows, for one. But several other things as well. I'm writing this post from the general linux-distro scene, and not just Ubuntu in specific. For the period before Feb, I'd been using Linux Mint as my primary OS for quite some time. But Ubuntu Natty Alpha brought all that Unity love (which I doted on once), and I had to move to 11.04&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reasons to switch to Linux&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its free!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its free! No more paying up for Windows. People who had Windows ship with their computers would be delighted to know that there is something called a Windows Refund, which allows you to be compensated by the cost of Windows, if you decide not to use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Better file system. If you've ever lost yourself in the mirth of files in &quot;Program Files&quot;, &quot;AppData&quot;, &quot;Application Data&quot;, &quot;sytem32&quot; and the like, you'd be delighted to know that there is a very well balanced binary management system in Linux. All binaries are in PATH, unlike Windows, where some softwares do that, and most don't. So you can actually run &lt;code&gt;php&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;ruby&lt;/code&gt; from any damn place that you want. People who have tried to compile Java programs using &lt;code&gt;javac&lt;/code&gt; on Windows might remembring updating PATH in Windows. No more of that in Linux.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free softwares! The majority of good software on Windows is paid (and even more with Mac). But in the Linux world, (almost) everything is free. What is paid for then? Some games, high level commercial softwares and the like. But most of the stuff is free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package Management&lt;/strong&gt; Apparently Windows 8 will have some sort of app-store with it. Which is a long time coming in Windows. But guess what, almost all Linux distros have some flavor of package manager built in. Debian (and Ubuntu) has &lt;code&gt;apt-get&lt;/code&gt;, Arch has &lt;code&gt;pacman&lt;/code&gt;, Fedora has &lt;code&gt;yum&lt;/code&gt;. And installing softwares is as easy as it could be. Need mysql? Just type &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install mysql&lt;/code&gt;. Done. Boom. Just like that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customization Level&lt;/strong&gt; Even though I don't like the messing up of Gnome by Ubuntu, there are tons of alternatives available. I'm right now using Gnome-Shell, and have plans to move to &lt;code&gt;xmonad&lt;/code&gt;, which is another Window Manager. Almost every feature on the Linux desktop can be customized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terminal&lt;/strong&gt; I'd always had planned several &lt;code&gt;learn bash scripting&lt;/code&gt; kind of to-dos but never got to it until I started using Linux. Even if you don't script, the actual power of your machine is opened by the terminal. Hacking away in &lt;code&gt;vim&lt;/code&gt;, and browsing sites using &lt;code&gt;elinks&lt;/code&gt;, and ordering Pizzas in Command Line is as geeky as it gets. Gnome is designed in such a way to allow a normal user to use his computer fully without touching the terminal, but if you use it, it gets better &amp;amp; better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications&lt;/strong&gt; There was a time I used to be a Windows fanatic, using WMP, Zune, Everything and what not. But now, I've got a bigger arsenal of softwares. Ever used &lt;em&gt;Audacious&lt;/em&gt;? That's my default music player, and its awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software Development&lt;/strong&gt; You use Windows to develop stuff for Windows. I'm nowhere near to writing applications in C#. I'll probably be hacking away scripts in ruby, node, python, bash, and building stuff using xul, gtk, webgtk, and qt. All my web applications are ultimately deployed on Linux machines, so it makes sense to write them on Linux. And only Linux has the ease of language package managers, like rubygems, npm, and pip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt; I haven't yet checked out the Linux Kernel source code, but I'm thinking of getting my hands dirty real soon. Ever since I've joined github, I've been introduced to several awesome coders, projects, and organizations. And guess what? Its all open source! Meaning I actually spend less time writing parsers for xml, and more time working on applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;What I've Learned&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be utterly fearless&lt;/strong&gt; Back when I was in Windows, a simple partition deletion used to scare me to death. Now? I'm ready for anything. If you, like me, go play with the alpha of all your favorite stuff, then things will break. And it will be fun to solve all that stuff. You will learn a thousand new things in the process, gain lots of rep on askubuntu, and become a Ubuntu Jedi Master. OK, maybe not the last bit, but &lt;em&gt;you shall become utterly fearless&lt;/em&gt; of all danger. I had to use my computer without network accesibility for three days. And it didn't even give me a GUI. So I just drudged along for 3 days straight on the console. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes, I feel people do not get my helpful comments, and offerings of help on Facebook. Its not their fault. They've never been introduced to a proper online, helpful community before. The Linux community is helpful, worldwide, readily available, and has probably handled the problem that you are facing now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server Administration&lt;/strong&gt; I'm still lacking on the cloud front, as I don't have servers powerful enough to host virtual machines. But otherwise, I've handled lots of stuff. &lt;code&gt;ssh&lt;/code&gt; is my thing, and I use &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; to deploy applications like a pro. I've moved on from &lt;code&gt;apache&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;nginx&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;cherokee&lt;/code&gt; and what not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Backups&lt;/strong&gt; Remember all those &quot;Take Backups before installing Windows/Ubuntu&quot; things that popup while installing your OS. I never paid attention to them, until recently. Now, I've got backups scheduled on &lt;code&gt;Dropbox&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;SpiderOak&lt;/code&gt;, and a custom &lt;code&gt;SparkleShare&lt;/code&gt; server. I make sure to host my code on github, or my personal git repositories and backup images to Picasa. Everyone knows hard discs are unreliable, so why not make your data redundant and take backups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The only counter argument would be that Windows has much more stream-lined view of things, with almost everything offering a GUI based application to amange stuff. That's just not the Linux way. Still, I'm not one of those crazy fanatics who go around preaching Linux (maybe I am!). I feel that if you are using your computer to just open Chrome, Firefox, VLC, and Word, then anything would do. You could probably install android on your computer and do everything you are doing right now. If you are a heavy gamer, then better stay with Windows. And if you are a programmer, switch to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Windows 8&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed a developer preview copy of Windows 8 recently, and although I was really awed by its designs concepts, I feel that it is still lacking in certain fronts. For instance, it seems to me that Microsoft is trying to get 8 to the tablets much more readily than on the desktops. Why? Because, there is nothing that can undermine Windows superior market share in Desktops for the near future. However Android &amp;amp; iOS have a very strong presence. Ergo, Windows 8 goes to tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I installed all my favorite programs on Windows 8, but had to switch back after a few days. As a developer, it just does not offer me the same freedom, and easy workflow that I am accustomed to. For instance :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installing Ruby with build support for gems took a lot of time and patience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cygwin does not compare anywhere near to a bash shell. Its like this tiny humble brother of shell who turns away when you say PATH. You have to type all those monstrous &lt;code&gt;C:/\&lt;/code&gt; kind of paths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No App Store. Windows 8 dev preview does not have an app store yet, which was one of the reasons I had tried Win8. I'm used to frequently browsing the Ubuntu Software Center just to find something that fits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I found that my productivity reduced to half when I was on Windows. I spent too much time looking for stuff which could be done by a single line bash on Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Tags: operating systems, linux, ubuntu, windows 8, weblog ifest 2011&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Programming in Node.JS</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/09/12/programming-in-nodejs/"/>
   <updated>2011-09-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/09/12/programming-in-nodejs</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After my attempts at &lt;a href=&quot;http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/05/16/learning-python&quot;&gt;python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rubyonrails.org&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt;, this was the time for node.js. You ask me what is node.js ? Remember when Google Chrome came out and went &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/40994/is-google-chromes-v8-engine-really-that-good&quot;&gt;blazing past the rest of the browsers&lt;/a&gt; in Javascript benchmarks. That was because of its internal Javascript Engine, called &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/v8/&quot;&gt;V8&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, V8 was developed as a backend to an evented IO library, that is now known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt;. Initially, it was named just node, but to prevent confusion, and explain its javascript inheritance, it was renamed node.js. This is the water-cooler moment of the language. If you know node, you're the cool guy on the block. So what is so special in node ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Evented IO&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically node allows you bring home the same good anonymous functions from &lt;a href=&quot;http://jquery.org&quot;&gt;JQuery&lt;/a&gt; on your server. In advanced terms, node allows evented input/output, meaning all the IO calls are non-blocking and evented, or scheduled in parallel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Traditional I/O:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
data = file.read(&quot;/foo/bar&quot;);
  // wait...
  doSomething(data);
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Evented I/O:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;
file.read(&quot;/foo/bar&quot;, function(data) {
  // called after data is read
  doSomething(data);
});
otherThing(); // execute immediately;
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;How To Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The official installation guide is present at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/Installation&quot;&gt;https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/Installation&lt;/a&gt;. I'd present a slightly different version, using &lt;code&gt;nvm&lt;/code&gt;, i.e &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/creationix/nvm&quot;&gt;Node Version Manager&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Unix/Linux&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Dependencies&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some dependencies on installing node.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install git-core build-essentials libssl-dev&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the corresponding command for your distro (yum etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Installing nvm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clone nvm:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/creationix/nvm.git ~/.nvm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include nvm:&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;code&gt;. ~/.nvm/nvm.sh&lt;/code&gt; //The dot is important&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source it to your bash file. Basically copy the above command(2) inside your ~/.bashrc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Fetching node&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Node is under heavy development at the moment. Development of node is carried across a stable &amp;amp; a testing branch. The stable branch is the one that you should prefer. As of now, &lt;code&gt;stable&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;v0.4.11&lt;/code&gt; and testing has reached &lt;code&gt;v0.5.6&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now run the following commands:
&lt;code&gt;nvm install v0.4.11&lt;/code&gt; to install v0.4.11
&lt;code&gt;nvm use v0.4.11&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;code&gt;nvm alias default v.04.11&lt;/code&gt; to make it default&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can type &lt;code&gt;which node&lt;/code&gt; to see the actual node binaries being used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Package Methods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would strongly advice against using your distro versions of node, unless you are on a rolling release distro, such as Arch. Please do not run &lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install node&lt;/code&gt; to install node. This would only cause much anguish and pain later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of now, even the beta of Ubuntu 11.10 holds &lt;code&gt;v0.4.9&lt;/code&gt; and is likely to do so for the next 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Windows&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I've stopped using Windows for quite some time, here are instructions from the official node installation guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows Build (Node v0.5.5)&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/dist/v0.5.5/node.exe&quot;&gt;http://nodejs.org/dist/v0.5.5/node.exe&lt;/a&gt;
I would again recommend to install &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/dist/v0.4.11/node.exe&quot;&gt;http://nodejs.org/dist/v0.4.11/node.exe&lt;/a&gt; for stability reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-contained binaries are available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://node-js.prcn.co.cc&quot;&gt;http://node-js.prcn.co.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Node Package Manager&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All cool programming languages come with their own package managers. Ruby has &lt;a href=&quot;htp://rubygems.org&quot;&gt;rubygems&lt;/a&gt;, Python has pip, PHP has PECL, perl has CPAN, and &lt;code&gt;node&lt;/code&gt; has &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/npm&quot;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt; holds a large collection of packages that are the extra batteries that don't come included in node. If you need to parse documents, or do some other fancy stuff in node, don't look farther than npm. If you need it, chances are, it already has a package in npm. See &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.npmjs.org/&quot;&gt;list of packages&lt;/a&gt; on the npm site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Unix&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple one line install is available for &lt;code&gt;npm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl http://npmjs.org/install.sh | sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, you can install any package by &lt;code&gt;npm install package&lt;/code&gt;. For instance, install jade by &lt;code&gt;npm install jade&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Windows folks can clone the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/isaacs/npm&quot;&gt;npm repository&lt;/a&gt; and run the included &lt;code&gt;nmp.bat&lt;/code&gt; file, and hope that it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Simple Servers in Node&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;node.js comes with &quot;batteries included&quot;, and part of that battery is node's ability to instantly create web servers. Yes, right inside your program, you can easily create web servers, which will hold full compliance to HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very simple HTTP server, written using the http module(included) in node :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint&quot;&gt;var http=require('http');
http.createServer(function(request, response) {
  var headers = { &quot;Content-Type&quot;: &quot;text/plain&quot; };
  response.sendHeader(200, headers);
  response.sendBody(&quot;Hello, World!\n&quot;);
  response.finish();
}).listen(8000);
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the createServer function takes a callback function as its argument. The callback function is called for each of the requests. All events are handled easily and instead of a server handling threads, memory etc, node just handles requests. In essence, a request generates an &lt;em&gt;event&lt;/em&gt;, which is then handled by the callback function provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is quite similar to the way we program event loops in javascript on the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The good stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are loads of interesting projects using node. Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/modules&quot;&gt;modules section&lt;/a&gt; on the node wiki for a list of interesting node modules available. These include node clients for various libraries such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/modules#wiki-database&quot;&gt;Databases&lt;/a&gt;(mysql, postgre, sqlite, Cassandra etc), Microframeworks (lik Sinatra), Frameworks, wikis, CMS, parsers and what not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd recommend starting out with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/senchalabs/Connect&quot;&gt;Connect&lt;/a&gt; which is a middleware for node, and allows you to wrap your application easily around it. For databases, you can either go with the standard Relational ones(like mysql) or be brave, and take a spin with the noSQL ones like CouchDB, Cassandra, or MongoDB. All of them have native bindings available for node.js.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joyent/node/&quot;&gt;Node On GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, including the wiki, documentation &amp;amp; code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;Nodejs.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Blogs &amp;amp; Other resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nodejitsu.com/&quot;&gt;NodeJitsu&lt;/a&gt;, a company working completely on node.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bytemuse.com/2011/06/getting-started-with-node-js-express-and-couchdb/&quot;&gt;Getting Started with Node.JS, Express and CouchDB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nodejitsu.com/6-must-have-nodejs-modules&quot;&gt;6 Must Have Node.js Modules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://addyosmani.com/blog/spotlight-issue1/&quot;&gt;Some cool node projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://howtonode.org/&quot;&gt;HowToNode&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nodebeginner.org/&quot;&gt;The node Beginner book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nodecasts.org/&quot;&gt;NodeCasts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com&quot;&gt;StackOverflow&lt;/a&gt; Questions on node&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/5869216&quot;&gt;How to store Node.js deployment settings/configuration files?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/2353818/how-do-i-get-started-with-nodejs&quot;&gt;How do I get started with NodeJS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1884724/what-is-node-js&quot;&gt;What is node.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/3648993/where-can-i-host-a-node-js-app&quot;&gt;Where to host node.js applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Tags : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/WeBlog2011&quot;&gt;WeBlog-iFest2011&lt;/a&gt;, Web Development, node.js&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning Ruby on Rails</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/08/01/learning-ruby-on-rails/"/>
   <updated>2011-08-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/08/01/learning-ruby-on-rails</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing my quest on Web Designing, I've started learning &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org&quot; title=&quot;Official RoR Site&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails&lt;/a&gt;, which is like &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; most-hyped web framefork of the moment. After all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com&quot; title=&quot;GitHub&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; runs on Ruby On Rails, &lt;a href=&quot;http://redmine.org&quot; title=&quot;A project management system with code browsing&quot;&gt;Redmine&lt;/a&gt; uses Rails, and so do &lt;a href=&quot;http://basecamphq.com&quot;&gt;Basecamp&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://hulu.com&quot;&gt;Hulu&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;http://scribd.com&quot;&gt;Scribd&lt;/a&gt;, and even &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Even though RoR has Ruby in its name, its just a namesake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning Ruby and learning Rails are entirely two different routes, and learning one only gives you a slight advantage in the other. I'm learning Rails by the excellent book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby.railstutorial.org/ruby-on-rails-tutorial-book&quot; title=&quot;Ruby On Rails 3 Tutorial&quot;&gt;Ruby On Rails 3 Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, by Michael Hartl. It covers Rails 3, which is one reason I picked it as Rails 3 is quite different from Rails 2 in comparision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails in a few words would be described as &lt;em&gt;a Web framework that makes writing web applications really, really easy&lt;/em&gt;. And I really mean that. I've been programming in Rails for ~2 days, and I can confortably say that it is better than any other PHP framework (viz &lt;a href=&quot;http://cakephp.org&quot;&gt;CakePHP&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://codeigniter.com&quot;&gt;CodeIgniter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kohanaphp.com&quot;&gt;Kohana&lt;/a&gt;) simple because it is powered by Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the beauty of Ruby is not in its implementation, but in its elegance. Reading ruby code is lie reading seeing a visual presentation. While PHP is the paragraphed, prose version of the same stuff. Simply put, PHP allows you to do the same things, but essentialy it was not readable enough to match Ruby's elegance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rails follows the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Model-view-controller&quot; title=&quot;Model View Conroller&quot;&gt;MVC pattern&lt;/a&gt; (Model-View-Controller) for development, and uses it strictly. It has got its own conventions, but as I found out, the concept of convention over Configuration makes much more sense in Rails than it ever did in PHP. All that time I spent in the CakePHP console was nothing compared to the interactivity of the Rails Console(&lt;code&gt;rails c&lt;/code&gt;). Starting development server(&lt;code&gt;rails s&lt;/code&gt;) is as easy as running the production server(&lt;code&gt;rails s --environment production&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of writing down &lt;em&gt;another&lt;/em&gt; beginner tutorial on Rails, I'd rather direct you to some of the excellent Rails resources :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ruby.railstutorial.org/ruby-on-rails-tutorial-book&quot; title=&quot;Ruby On Rails 3 Tutorial&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails 3 Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, the book I'm reading for learning Rails. Highly recommended&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://railsbrains.org&quot;&gt;RailsBrains&lt;/a&gt;, offline API for Rails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://guides.rubyonrails.org/getting_started.html&quot;&gt;Rails Getting Started&lt;/a&gt;, Official Rails Getting Started guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/ruby-on-rails&quot;&gt;Rails@Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Announcing Planet IITR</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/07/09/announcing-planet-iitr/"/>
   <updated>2011-07-09T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/07/09/announcing-planet-iitr</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr/&quot;&gt;Planet IIT-R&lt;/a&gt; is a blog collection similar to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://planet.ubuntu.com&quot;&gt;Planet Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://planet.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;, and the likes. The basic idea is to create a single address where all blogs of IIT-R are aggregated. This way, people can easily follow happenings and blogs at IIT-Roorkee without individually following various blogs. I've added a few blogs to it already, including those of &lt;a href=&quot;http://divye.in&quot;&gt;Divye Kapoor&lt;/a&gt;, Sanath Rath, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wona.co.in&quot;&gt;Wona&lt;/a&gt;, Arasu and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A complete list of blogs in the planet is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr/subscriptions/&quot;&gt;http://www.planetaki.com/iitr/subscriptions/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: There is also a feature in planetaki to suggest a website for the planet. Unfortunately, you need to be logged in to planetaki (ie create a planet) to suggest a site. In case you are, you can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetaki.com/iitr/subscriptions/suggest&quot;&gt;the suggestions&lt;/a&gt; feature to suggest websites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To suggest a blog to add to the list, please use the form below. You can also see the current spreadsheet &lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadsheets.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?hl=en_US&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;key=0AmqzfUR1eWkldHdGSTNOM1kyZVEtRElWU0xsYkZVZ1E&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=0&amp;amp;output=html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://spreadsheets.google.com/spreadsheet/embeddedform?formkey=dHdGSTNOM1kyZVEtRElWU0xsYkZVZ1E6MQ&quot; width=&quot;760&quot; height=&quot;643&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot;&gt;Loading...&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
You can also &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; for any further queries.&lt;br/&gt;
Further Links :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planetaki.com&quot;&gt;http://planetaki.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://planetplanet.com&quot;&gt;http://planetplanet.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://spreadsheets.google.com/spreadsheet/pub?hl=en_US&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;key=0AmqzfUR1eWkldHdGSTNOM1kyZVEtRElWU0xsYkZVZ1E&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;gid=0&amp;amp;output=html&quot;&gt;Spreadsheet of the form above&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What if Linus Torvalds designed Google+</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/07/07/linus/"/>
   <updated>2011-07-07T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/07/07/linus</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Google's announced its next big thing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.google.com&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; to take on Facebook left people wondering if the next version would be called Google++. Inspite of all the great work that Vic Gundotra has put into Google+, it still lacks something. The creator of linux, Linus Torvalds. Google+ is as-of-now the social network for tech-geeks who are part of a field trial experiment(monkeys!) on the site. Google+ is still halfway geek, and in my imagination it would have been the ultimate geek power tool if it had been designed by Linus. Unfortunately, he is busy developing the linux kernel (10 million lines, 2% being his), and we would have to suffice with these thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open Source&lt;/strong&gt; : Google+ would be open sourced. Anyone could run Google+ on their own servers, and use it to create their own Social Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Command Line&lt;/strong&gt; : The default Google+ client would run natively on linux/unix but would be ported later to Windows using cygwin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulty-of-use&lt;/strong&gt; : Gone are the click and point days. You'd be required to have absolute mastery over at least 5 different commands before you can even post a single item to your feed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Control&lt;/strong&gt; : You will have full control over whatever you post. You can make 4 changes, stage them, take them back, commit 2 of them, edit a post, and recommit before pushing it to the server. However all of this will be stored.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Git Backend&lt;/strong&gt; : Both the client and the server will use git as its backend to store history, revisions, links, and circles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Circles&lt;/strong&gt; : would be called trees. And you can tag your trees to take a snapshot of your friends lists at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branching&lt;/strong&gt; : would allow you to create multiple versions of your profile. The default version will be called master, while you can continue your secret development in alpha, staging, beta branches. Circles will automatically be associated with branches and auto-post items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merging&lt;/strong&gt; : will allow for collaborative posts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 12 years of development, Google+ will reach version 2.1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No deletions&lt;/strong&gt; : Everything in history has an importance. You are allowed to use rebase to rewrite history. Beware: use cautiously. Incorrect usage may lead to painfull scenarios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mascot(direwolf ?) would be found for Google+ (probably after it bit Linus in an aquarium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook would spend $421m fighting Google+&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The manual of Google+ would be a labryinth of switches amd command line arguments for all the features that it came with. A user would be expected to read through the entire manual, or at least the first one-third, before being able to &lt;em&gt;do something&lt;/em&gt; of use with the service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To block a user, you must enter his id in an ignore file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3 years hence, the next big thing would be ghub offering a farm-like service to create, host, and customize your own google+ servers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: Based on the history of linux, and the usability of git.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Announcement&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thelinuxdaily.com/2010/04/the-first-linux-announcement-from-linus-torvalds/&quot;&gt;famous announcement of Linux Kernel&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;code&gt;comp.os.minix&lt;/code&gt; mailing list is well-known. Slightly re-written, this is how Linus might have announced Google+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&gt;From: torvalds@klaava.Helsinki.FI (Linus Benedict Torvalds)  
&gt;Newsgroups: web.social.facebook  
&gt;Subject: What would you like to see most in facebook  
&gt;Summary: small poll for my new social network  
&gt;Message-ID: &lt;2011Jun28.205708.9541@klaava.Helsinki.FI&gt;  
&gt;Date: 28 Jun 11 20:57:08 GMT  
&gt;Organization: Google  

&gt;Hello everybody out there using facebook -

&gt;Im doing a (free) social network (just a hobby, wont be big and professional like facebook). This has been brewing since dec, and is starting to get ready. Id like any feedback on things people like/dislike in facebook, as my site resembles it somewhat (same layout of the news feed and comments(due to practical reasons) among other things).

&gt;Ive currently ported feed(1.08), comments(2.1), photos(3.14), and likes(1.40), and things seem to work. This implies that Ill get something practical within a few months, and Id like to know what features most people would want. Any suggestions are welcome, but I wont promise Ill implement them :-)

&gt;Linus (torvalds@kruuna.helsinki.fi)

&gt;PS. Yes  its free of any facebook code, and it has pipelined js. It is NOT protable (uses google accounts), and it probably never will support anything other than Google App Engine, as thats all I have :-(.

&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Tags: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/WeBlog2011&quot;&gt;WeBlog iFest 2011&lt;/a&gt;, humour, linux, linus&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Why Indian Government Sucks at Technology</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/06/22/why-indian-government-sucks-at-technology/"/>
   <updated>2011-06-22T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/06/22/why-indian-government-sucks-at-technology</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Why The Indian Government sucks at technology&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: All opinions are mine alone. Please keep your opinions limited to comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is in wake of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voiceofgreyhat.com/2011/06/anonymous-withdrawn-op-india-untold.html&quot; title=&quot;Aftermath of the attack&quot;&gt;not-so-anonymous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thehackernews.com/2011/06/anonymous-india-opindia-strikes-again.html&quot; title=&quot;News report of the actual event&quot;&gt;attacks&lt;/a&gt; on the nic servers. Apparently a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pastebin.com/MHwHNTEi&quot; title=&quot;Names of perpetrators of the hack&quot;&gt;few people&lt;/a&gt; had decided to brand their own version of AnonymousIndia and hack into the nic servers. This had been viewed as almost normal in the Indian Media. This is after all something that happens every other day in India. Its just the Indian Army website, nothing that we care about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though there are excellent &lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.nullcon.net/&quot; title=&quot;Jobs in indian security sector&quot;&gt;tech-security companies in India&lt;/a&gt;, we have never developed the right attitude to it. People still think that hacking is fun, and its something that could never happen to them. I've never seen people reading the fine print on the thousand social web sites they join now a days. Piracy is rampant in India without any checks and the Indian Government is silent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why? Because we are used to it. It has always happened this way. Information leaks have been a major part of the Indian history and would remain so unless we realize that the more we embrace technology; the more we become dependent on it, it is coming one step closer to the edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent tweet by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/#!/divyekapoor/&quot; title=&quot;@divyekapoor on twitter&quot;&gt;@divyekapoor&lt;/a&gt; reminded me of the AADHAR project, which aims to give out a unique identification number to each Indian citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- http://twitter.com/#!/divyekapoor/status/82123483202584576 --&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;style type='text/css'&gt;.bbpBox82123483202584576 {background:#557799;padding:20px;} p.bbpTweet{background:#fff;padding:10px 12px 10px 12px;margin:0;min-height:48px;color:#000;font-size:18px !important;line-height:22px;-moz-border-radius:5px;-webkit-border-radius:5px} p.bbpTweet span.metadata{display:block;width:100%;clear:both;margin-top:8px;padding-top:12px;height:40px;border-top:1px solid #fff;border-top:1px solid #e6e6e6} p.bbpTweet span.metadata span.author{line-height:19px} p.bbpTweet span.metadata span.author img{float:left;margin:0 7px 0 0px;width:38px;height:38px} p.bbpTweet a:hover{text-decoration:underline}p.bbpTweet span.timestamp{font-size:12px;display:block}&lt;/style&gt; &lt;div class='bbpBox82123483202584576'&gt;&lt;p class='bbpTweet'&gt;Hacks like these ensure that I will resist giving my Biometrics to the UID project till they've suffered atleast 4 security breaches.&lt;span class='timestamp'&gt;&lt;a title='Sat Jun 18 16:32:18 +0000 2011' href='http://twitter.com/#!/divyekapoor/status/82123483202584576'&gt;quite some time time ago&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/download/android&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Twitter for Android&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/intent/favorite?tweet_id=82123483202584576'&gt;&lt;img src='http://si0.twimg.com/images/dev/cms/intents/icons/favorite.png' /&gt; Favorite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/intent/retweet?tweet_id=82123483202584576'&gt;&lt;img src='http://si0.twimg.com/images/dev/cms/intents/icons/retweet.png' /&gt; Retweet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/intent/tweet?in_reply_to=82123483202584576'&gt;&lt;img src='http://si0.twimg.com/images/dev/cms/intents/icons/reply.png' /&gt; Reply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class='metadata'&gt;&lt;span class='author'&gt;&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/divyekapoor'&gt;&lt;img src='http://a3.twimg.com/profile_images/1335737598/221976_10150170015204512_515029511_6682584_156881_n_normal.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://twitter.com/divyekapoor'&gt;Divye Kapoor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;divyekapoor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;


&lt;!-- end of tweet --&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I read out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://uidai.gov.in/&quot; title=&quot;Official Website&quot;&gt;UIDAI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://uidai.gov.in/UID_PDF/Front_Page_Articles/MOU/MOUsSigned/MOU_Uttarakhand.pdf&quot; title=&quot;UIDAI's 'MOU With the uttrakhand govt.&quot;&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; and it tells us that it would  &lt;em&gt;&quot;prescribe protocols to ensure the confidentiality, privacy and security  of data&quot;&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;&quot;follow the confidentiality, privacy and security  protocols prescribed by the UIDAI&quot;&lt;/em&gt;. A search on the uidai.gov.in website gives out a little detail :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UID database will be guarded both physically and electronically by a few select individuals with high clearance. It will not be available even for many members of the UID staff and will be secured with the best encryption, and in a highly secure data vault. All access details will be properly logged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the most that they have to say on the subject. If that makes you feel safe, remember the earlier fiasco involving the security of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://indiaevm.org/&quot; title=&quot;Website of the security researchers detailing their study on tampering of EVMs&quot;&gt;EVM machines&lt;/a&gt;. Ultimately I'm with the government on that one, however, since a user had to have physical access to actually do any harm to the machine. But &lt;em&gt;it was possible&lt;/em&gt; and Election Council kept denying it. As it happened, it seems that all our govt. agencies are probably trying more to hide their technical requirements, rather than make them open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is this approach taken in India? Beauracracy? probably yes. But I feel that unless the technocrats rise up and actually enter the Indian Govt. technical agencies (such as NIC), nothing would change. For instance I find that almost everything that Indian government does is tailored specifically for Windows. There is no reason to plaster &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=Internet%20Explorer%20site:gov.in%20-filetype:pdf&quot; title=&quot;List of indian government websites with the words Internet Explorer&quot;&gt;&quot;Works best in Internet Explorer 6 at 1024x768&quot;&lt;/a&gt; in all your web sites, we already know how much the &lt;a href=&quot;http://techrights.org/wiki/index.php/Microsoft_influence_in_the_Indian_government&quot; title=&quot;Microsoft's Influence in the Indian Government&quot;&gt;Indian&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://techrights.org/2010/01/22/india-patents-microsoft-lobby/&quot;&gt;government&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ramdas.diqtech.com/blogs/2008/jun/16/how-microsoft-has-locked-the-indian-government/&quot; title=&quot;Microsft has locked the Indian Government&quot;&gt;loves Windows&lt;/a&gt;. So much so that they get it pre-installed everywhere, even in government schools, and technical institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there is a small faction that is working tirelessly in the other direction as well. For instance the &lt;a href=&quot;http://technorati.com/technology/gadgets/article/sakshat-a-35-tablet-to-be/&quot; title=&quot;Technorati's report on the device with specs of the tablet&quot;&gt;Sakshat project&lt;/a&gt; has been under the news recently as well. It would ship with a version of android (which one?) with wi-fi, bluetooth and other frills. However the project has been known for shadowing and changing its details at each conference it is unvealed, so beware. It may suddenly change from an android to a Windows phone in the next one. Or maybe a blade server (speaking of which, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uidai.gov.in/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=177&amp;amp;Itemid=214&quot; title=&quot;List of contracts awareded by UIDAI&quot;&gt;uid project ordered 68 of them&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've worked a little bit on online Geo-Mapping tools earlier (mostly using Google Maps API). However, I wanted some accurate data for one of my projects (such as geographical boundaries). Other sources for this data are not as reliable, and I found the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bhuvan3.nrsc.gov.in/&quot; title=&quot;Bhuvan is a Google Earth like mapping tool developed by ISRO&quot;&gt;bhuvan online tool&lt;/a&gt; to be extremely accurate in this respect. If you've forgotten &lt;a href=&quot;http://bhuvan.nrsc.gov.in/bhuvan/&quot; title=&quot;Official site&quot;&gt;Bhuvan&lt;/a&gt;, its the Indian version of Google Maps. It was supposed to be &lt;strong&gt;the tool for mapping things&lt;/strong&gt;. Unfortunately, as things have planned out, most of its &lt;a href=&quot;http://ogleearth.com/2008/11/bhuvan-indias-upcoming-web-map-announced-misreported/&quot; title=&quot;Bhuvan not what it was supposed to be&quot;&gt;claims have been rubbished&lt;/a&gt; (like 10m resolution power), or made null due to the extremely slow servers it uses(and it was supposedly optimized for low bandwidths). If you're plannig to fight google, you've to step up your game. Try checking out the horrible design of the Bhuvan website. Leaving aside its horrible interface, Windows only support (.net), installation of additional plugins to just run it, and , it had brilliant geographical data(collected via various government agencies). However as it turns out, this data is not public. Why? It seems that ISRO plans to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dnaindia.com/india/report_bhuvan-our-answer-to-google-earth-soon_1203871&quot;&gt;sell this data&lt;/a&gt; to people interested in using it. Wow! So a public funded agency decides to make money from the development done using &lt;em&gt;our money&lt;/em&gt;. It's been close to 3 years since its launch. And I'd be highly interested in knowing where it managed to sell this data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all fairness, though they've said that they would only sell the high resolution data, while making the general data &lt;em&gt;freely available to users&lt;/em&gt;. But I don't see fair unless its own my system, damn it. If by free you mean I'd have to open your website each time I need to find a village, it seems we have different thoughts about the word's usage. Oh, and there's a link on the website's home page to a section called APIs which redirects to the Bhuvan Software download page, where guess what, there are no APIs at all. I managed to dig a few links and download two versions of their APIs, which seem to be downloaded copies of the documentation of the open layer javascript protocol they are using for mapping in the browser. So the data is available, it seems. But they're forgetting to mention where.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, people wake up. This is the 21st century, and the most hyped buzz word today is open-source(well, after cloud). And if you really want to work on things, make them open source. Not just the technology, but the data as well. Becauase open data is essential to growth and planning of a nation, as Hans Rosling keeps on reminding us. Meanwhile, DRDO decides to go ahead and &lt;a href=&quot;http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2010-10-10/news/28458329_1_saraswat-drdo-cyber-attacks&quot;&gt;develop its own operating system&lt;/a&gt;. Why? Because it will be closed-source and will be much more secure than any of the variants of linux.  Or so they think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Informatics center still runs thousands of its websites in ASP (not even ASP.net), and this fact alone is enough to scare me off. With major corporations suffering from data leakage (Sony, Gawker) where user access was compromised, it is high time that the Indian Govt. someone realizes that you cannot secure your systems by locking them in a vault. These companies did the same, and look at the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the American Government has come up with an open-source initiative. Their website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.data.gov&quot;&gt;data.gov&lt;/a&gt; is a collection of applications, apis and raw data collected by various government agencies. And to top it all, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.govtech.com/e-government/White-House-Honors-Unsung-Open-Data-App-Developers.html&quot;&gt;US government invited the top application developers&lt;/a&gt; from their platform at data.gov to the White House, hailing them as unsung heroes of the new age. If you're interested in reading more and taking a stand for the open data democracy, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://share-psi.eu/papers/TNO.pdf&quot;&gt;this whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; by the Netherlands Organisation for Applied Scientific Research for a keen review of what are the major barriers to a government from sharing its data. Also go ahead and donate some money to wikileaks, while you're at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And where is the Indian government at this? Not &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; far behind, but lagging nonetheless. Let us take the prime example of the decennial festival that is the Census. Apparently all census data is free (as it should be). But there is a minor caveat. The entire site is made in asp (which doesn't really matter, I just don't like it), and all the data (tables, figures, maps) are in pdf format. So, you can access the data personally, on a single page. Page by page, it might be thousands of documents, figures, charts, and what not. But since it is all in pdf format, it is locked down. You could parse it by some means, but the data is supposed to be free, in the best format possible so that everyone can use it easily. And the geographical boundary data(which I mentioned earlier) is also available in the census results, but only via a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.censusindia.gov.in/maps/censusgis/Census_GIS/page/India_WhizMap/IndiaMap.htm&quot; title=&quot;Developed by Whizmaps, Riddhi softwares&quot;&gt;java applet&lt;/a&gt;, which does not allow access to the raw data, that an application developer would need. Am I expected to file an RTI application, just to know the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; boundaries of my state. Or perhaps, I should just pay ISRO and be done with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an &lt;del&gt;additional benifit&lt;/del&gt; &lt;ins&gt;easter egg&lt;/ins&gt;, the census website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.censusindia.gov.in/Footer_Menus/Disclaimer.html&quot;&gt;states the following&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Census of India or any data or content providers shall not be liable for any errors in the content, or for any actions taken in reliance thereon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All efforts have been made to ensure the accuracy and currency of the content on this website. However, users are requested to verify/check any information with us to obtain appropriate professional advice before acting on the information provided in the website. In no event will the Government or office of the Registrar General India be liable for any expense, loss or damage including, without limitation, indirect or consequential loss or damage, or any expense, loss or damage whatsoever arising from use, or loss of use, of data, arising out of or in connection with the use of this website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, as an analogue to the excellent Right To Information Act, there must be an analogous Right To Technology act. It should empower each and every person in the country to know what is happening behind the scenes. We demand total transparency in technological decisions. Not just the passing of tenders, but the decisions which involve actual technological development. For. eg at the CDAC website, the government offers a trial version of various forensic tools they've developed. Why aren't they open sourced? Why were they writen using a particular language? If RTI fought off the beauracracy, this could help us eliminate the old technocrat thinking from the India Govt. If we are able to get the right data, in the right format, thousands of application developers across the world are willing to create great ways to access that data. Data by itself is not enough, however. It must be met with an equal resolve from people to make it accesible, and usable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a turning point in the Indian Govt. Either they could continue what they've been doing and meet their doom in a major state sponsored hack crippling the entire nation. Or they could take a step back, and do things the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And what is the right way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/peace-love-linux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Peace, Love, Linux&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; :According to an article in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/international-business/all-new-e-governance-projects-must-work-on-open-source-operating-systems-draft/articleshow/9119827.cms&quot;&gt;Economic Times&lt;/a&gt;, there is a working draft for bringing Open-Source in e-governence systems under work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Setting Up Sparkleshare Server using Gitolite and Ubuntu</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/06/20/ubuntu-gitolite-sparkleshare-install/"/>
   <updated>2011-06-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/06/20/ubuntu-gitolite-sparkleshare-install</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody seems to be all about open-source cloud-backup and sync solutions now-a-days. The hype is all around the cloud, they say. However cloud is just a stupid &lt;a href=&quot;http://everythingsysadmin.com/2011/06/avoid-using-the-term-cloud-com.html&quot;&gt;concept for sales people&lt;/a&gt;, that I prefer to avoid. However people are coming up with all kinds of crazy ideas to create their own &lt;a href=&quot;http://fak3r.com/geek/howto-build-your-own-open-source-dropbox-clone/&quot;&gt;dropbox&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rubyinside.com/rubydrop-a-dropbox-clone-in-ruby-3968.html&quot;&gt;clones&lt;/a&gt;. A few similar services include &lt;a href=&quot;https://spideroak.com/&quot;&gt;SpiderOak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://one.ubuntu.com/&quot;&gt;Ubuntu One&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sugarsync.com/&quot;&gt;Sugar Sync&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wuala.com/&quot;&gt;Wuala&lt;/a&gt;. However, not all of them are compatible with Linux (unlike Dropbox, which is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Comparision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here's a minor comparision of some famous clients :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; : Cuurent Leader, offers everything from sync, collaboration, sharing, public links, upgradable storage and is &lt;em&gt;the de-facto&lt;/em&gt; client for synchonization tasks. However there have been a few issues regarding its privacy issues recently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ubuntu One&lt;/strong&gt; : Ubuntu One is Ubuntu's fighting offering to Dropbox. Its excellent, with an open source api, that allows one to create applications for the Ubuntu One platform very easily. However, the server-side of Ubuntu-One is still closed source, which means you cannot setup it on your own servers (similar to dropbox). Canonical has hinted that it might be made open source in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wuala&lt;/strong&gt; : is a file-backup network where you trade your own hard disk space for extra storage. This allows wuala to offer higher space at a much lower offering rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpiderOak&lt;/strong&gt; : I'm using this currently along with SparkleShare and Dropbox. It has proven to be very robust, allowing me to backup almost anything to its servers. I've got a 5GB account which is more than enough for me till now. Its very powerful interface allows one to control each and every aspect of your backup/sync/share process. Also it boasts of a true-privacy feature, meaning that all your documents are encrypted before being sent to dropbox. It also means that you can only reset your password from your own computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_file_synchronization_software&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comparison_of_file_synchronization_software&lt;/a&gt; for a better comparision of several other services as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Installing SparkleShare using gitolite&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a simple tutorial on running your own sparkleshare server as a hosting server. Note, that this implementation should ideally be built as a separate module for sparkleshare-admin, which is still under works as of writing. Sparkleshare's basic concept is to use git repositories as storage places. In case you don't know what git is, I'd recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://git.wiki.kernel.org/index.php/GitFaq&quot;&gt;this guide&lt;/a&gt; for more details. In short it is an awesome revisioning system for use by anyone managing code(or content for that matter as well). It allows you to keep track of what is happening with your directory, and revert back to earlier versions (among &lt;strong&gt;several&lt;/strong&gt; other things).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sparkleshare asks you to setup a git-server somewhere and use it as a remote storage system. It offers out of the box support for git hosting providers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.github.com&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitorious.org/&quot;&gt;gitorious&lt;/a&gt;. It also allows you to add your own custom servers as well. Enough description, lets get down to some work :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Setup Gitolite&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Assumptions :&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You are running a stable Linux OS (Fedore/Debian/Ubuntu etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;user@host1&lt;/code&gt; is your own computer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;user2@host2&lt;/code&gt; is the primary computer where you intend to start the server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gitolite username is &lt;code&gt;sparkle&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-sh&quot;&gt;
#On your host machine (which will be remote admin to the git share)
ssh-copy-id user2@host2:/tmp/user.tmp
#should not ask for password:
ssh user2@host2
sudo apt-get install gitolite 
sudo dpkg-reconfigure sparkleshare
#Configuration Options may vary, but remember the gitolite user name that you specified
logout #Come back to your own computer
git clone sparkle@host2:gitolite-admin 
#Should work, or else you did something wrong. Go read the [gitolite docs](http://sitaramc.github.com/gitolite/doc/)
cd gitolite-admin
nano conf/gitolite.conf
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Setup WildRepos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit the file and add the following lines at the bottom :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-pl&quot;&gt;
repo    share/[a-z0-9]{6}
    C   =   @all
    RW+ =   CREATOR
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now we need a method to allow anyone to create git repositories on the server. This is accomplished via Gitolite's very powerful Wildcard Repositories feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-sh&quot;&gt;
#Login back to server
ssh user2@host2
#Since we are using package install method, sparkle's password needs to be set
sudo passwd sparkle
su - sparkle
nano .gitolite.rc
#search for $GL_WILDREPOS and set it to 1
logout
#Now we push our admin repo to add the wildrepo settings
#you're still inside the gitolite-admin directory, right
git push
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Setup Client&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, your server is all setup, but there is still stuff to be done :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-sh&quot;&gt;
#On user1@host1
mkdir -p ~/.ssh
sudo add-apt-repository ppa:warp10/sparkleshare
sudo apt-get update
sudo apt-get install sparkleshare libwebkit1.1-cil git-core
sparkleshare start &amp;
sparkleshare stop
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When you run sparkleshare for the first time, it asks you for a few things, including your email-id. Fill in those details, but do not setup your repository yet. You need to first allow your sparkleshare account access to gitolite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-sh&quot;&gt;
cd ~/.config/sparkleshare
ls #Should reveal files called sparkleshare.email.key and sparkleshare.email.key.pub
cp sparkleshare.email.key.pub /path/to/gitolite-admin/keydir/
cd /path/to/gitolite-admin/
git commit -am &quot;Added sparkleshare client1&quot;
git push
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now if all goes well, you'd have allowed acess to gitolite for this user. We now need to re-run the sparkeshare setup again. Find it in your Applications. Now when it asks you to fill a repository path, type in the following details :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;prettyprint lang-yaml&quot;&gt;
Server: sparkle@host2
Path: /share/fh73ah
&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Please take care of the slashes, otherwise sparkleshare fails to recognize it as a valid ssh address. Instead of fh73ah, you can type any alphanumeric string of 6 characters. You can change this in your gitolite-admin conf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your first sync is complete (in which it tries to clone your existing repo, and gitolite creates it for you), you can find a folder called Sparkleshare in your home directory. This contains all your personal sparkleshares, including your first one. Put in any content inside the fh73ah and it would be automatically synchronized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about sparkleshare is that you can use your own server under your own rules. I've synced 143GB via Sparkleshare so far, and it has been working excellent so far. It takes a complete history, takes care of moves (git) and allows you to keeo huge backups easily. Just drag and drop, and forget. If you want to sync already existing folders, just drag them , and alt+drop them inside the shared folder. This way a sym-link gets created, which refers to the original directory. The sparkleshare folder on my computer takes up hardly a few kbs, but syncs worth 150gb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is only useful if you need to manage multiple accounts on the same host. Otherwise, you can refer to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webupd8.org/2011/03/set-up-sparkleshare-with-your-own.html&quot;&gt;excellent post&lt;/a&gt; on webupd8 for instructions to install it to a single user system (which does not involve the complication of gitolite). I've been looking for some gitolite management scripts (I've written a few as well) which would allow one to easily add their own ssh keys. This way anyone can easily setup accounts on the system. However, as of now, this is just a dream.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Website [ CaptNemo.in]</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/06/13/new-website-captnemo-in/"/>
   <updated>2011-06-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/06/13/new-website-captnemo-in</id>
   <content type="html">Just if someone's still following this blog around(don't, its already dead).

&amp;nbsp;

I've moved over to my new website (&lt;a title=&quot;CaptNemo.in&quot; href=&quot;http://www.captnemo.in&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.captnemo.in&lt;/a&gt;). Its running from github and will be a perfectly static website where the power of my awesome magical skills shall finally be revealed.

Just joking. Its hosted on the awesome servers of github and you might want to check it out..
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>IIT-JEE 2011 Results</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/06/01/iit-jee/"/>
   <updated>2011-06-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/06/01/iit-jee</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I worked out the entire IIT-JEE 2011 results and the end result is available &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/iitjee&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In case anyone finds any errors in the data, please open an issueat &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/captn3m0.github.com/issues&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. You can also contact me by &lt;a href=&quot;/contact/&quot;&gt;other means&lt;/a&gt;. As always a disclaimer applies, and I'm not responsible for any mistakes in this listing. I've intentionally removed the Application Form Number (partially) in the results, so that it may not be misused. I'm thinking of trying a full-scale birthday permutation attempt on the JEE site for the Application Form. What do you think? Will it be worth it?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning Python, PyGTK</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/05/16/learning-python/"/>
   <updated>2011-05-16T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/05/16/learning-python</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I had been meaning to learn either Python or Ruby for a long time but had been unable to decide. I had a basic understanding of both of these, but I never had the chance to build an entire application in either. And I'm not talking about using &lt;a href=&quot;http://djangoproject.com&quot; title=&quot;Django is a web framework for Python&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://rubyonrails.org&quot; title=&quot;Ruby on Rails is a web framework for Ruby&quot;&gt;Ruby on Rails&lt;/a&gt; (which are both brilliant), but building a desktop application using GTK.
The application I was first aiming for was a P2P sharing client which would be completely decentralized and offer several special features, such as :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAT Transversal using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UDP_hole_punching&quot;&gt;UDP Hole Punching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTP based file sharing as well (so that people can install their clients, and &lt;strong&gt;still use&lt;/strong&gt; IDM for downloading stuff)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client discovery &amp;amp; routing behind firewalls along the lines of Skype (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.h-online.com/security/features/How-Skype-Co-get-round-firewalls-747197.html&quot;&gt;using supernodes&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However my dreams were shattered by the first point itself, being the difficulty of NAT Transversals. Further ahead was the question of networking as well, which could have potentially driven me nuts. I worked a bit on it, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/STUN&quot; title=&quot;Stun is a NAT transversal server&quot;&gt;STUN&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://twistedmatrix.com&quot; title=&quot;Twisted is a networking framework for Python&quot;&gt;twisted&lt;/a&gt;, but gave up on it soon as being unfeasable as a learning project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next idea came to me when I got tired of downloading stuff using &lt;a href=&quot;http://axel.alioth.debian.org/&quot; title=&quot;Axel is a multithreaded download binary&quot;&gt;axel&lt;/a&gt; from the command line and started itching for something similar to &lt;a href=&quot;http://internetdownloadmanager.com&quot;&gt;Internet Download Manger&lt;/a&gt; for Ubuntu. The closest thing to a download manager on Ubuntu is &lt;a href=&quot;http://fatrat.dolezel.info/&quot;&gt;FatRat&lt;/a&gt; and is something I really don't like. It is based on Qt and prouds on working as a front-end for several file-sharing websites as well. What I needed was in fact a fast download manager, which keeps tracks of what I download, and does not require keeping a terminal open all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.gnome.org/gwget/&quot;&gt;GwGet&lt;/a&gt;, which occassionaly looks much better in the source version than in the one from the Ubuntu Repositories. I really liked this one, except for the fact that it was made using C++, and used single threaded downloads (like wget). As a result it was quite slow, and not upto my needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was when I thought of the idea of creating a download manger using [GTK] [gtk] +  Python/Ruby. I looked around for axel ports in Python/Ruby and found &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pyaxel/&quot; title=&quot;Axel port to python&quot;&gt;PyAxel&lt;/a&gt;, which beat axel in some of my benchmarks (after &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/pyaxel/issues/detail?id=4&quot; title=&quot;My patch for optimizing PyAxel's chunk size&quot;&gt;this patch&lt;/a&gt;). For the past two days, I have been working on PyGTK, Glade, Anjuta and several other IDEs, none of them to my liking. I really prefer Vim :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/pget&quot; title=&quot;PGet home page on Github&quot;&gt;PGet&lt;/a&gt; has been minimal. I've worked out threading, and little parts of GUI which were stripped from GwGet. As of now, it is still under works, but I am hoping for a release real soon. After all, it is not for nothing that they call Python a dynamic langugae&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more details, please go the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/pget&quot; title=&quot;PGet home page on Github&quot;&gt;PGet&lt;/a&gt; project page on Github. I will be posting further updates over there.
In case someone is following this blog, you can view the source for this website at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/captn3m0/captn3m0.github.com&quot; title=&quot;This website on GitHub&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt; and maybe even fork it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Puzzles, Life &amp; Other Things</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/04/30/puzzles/"/>
   <updated>2011-04-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/04/30/puzzles</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I've already decided to make this my newer blog, why not just continue in the same spirit and write a little of the events of my highly boring, lazy life. For one, I was part of the SDSLabs 1st yearly trip to Robber's Caves which was highly enthralling. We enjoyed a lot, and as a bonus I learned to play Mafia. Somehow the concept of not-knowing and yet trying to deduce out a solution in Mafia seems quite interesting for a Party game to me. Among other things, my sister got me a new Rubik Cube (which should be my 6th or 7th I guess), and I've been practising quite a lot (to the dismay of my friends and teachers), My timings have not been upto the mark as they were last year, but I've been improving and I average around 80 seconds per solve. I've been focusing on learning the entire Fridrich, and try to learn 2-3 moves per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spent some time reading a brilliant new fantasy series called &quot;The Kingkiller Chronicles&quot; by Patrick Rothfuss. It is a brilliant new debut series in fantasy fiction, and already has 2 books out from its planned trilogy : The name of the Wind, and The Wise Man's Fear. The series is highly praised, and you were to believe me, one of the best pieces of Fantasy ever written. But it is not the fantasy about this book that makes it so great. Its the general themes of love, tragedy, enemity, and knowledge that make it brilliant. Kvothe, the protagonist of the series is a charming character who is telling the story of his life to the Chronicler. Enough on the book, just go ahead and read it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I've got a RSS feed for blog using Jekyll already. Its available [here] (/atom.xml)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Game Of Thrones</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/04/19/game-of-thrones/"/>
   <updated>2011-04-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/04/19/game-of-thrones</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, Game Of Thrones is a high budget fantasy TV series currently being screened on HBO. It is based on George R.R Martin's epic fantasy, A Song Of Fire &amp;amp; Ice, book one of the Game Of Thrones series.
I had started reading the book a few weeks ago (not knowing then about the TV series), but never quite got the time. However after the highly promoted Trailer, and the absolutely brilliant episode 1, I've picked up the book once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've decided to keep myself aloof from all the spoilers, and read the book along with the series. This means that I will be finishing the book in a very long time, but also that I will be able to get a much better insight into what is going on the series. For eg there are very many characters in the TV series, which are not yet introduced, and it was interesting to see them come upfront in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is anyone else reading the book for the first time along with the TV series ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the ground from the book that each episode contains. I will continue to update this as the series goes ahead :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Episode :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 1-8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 9-17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 18-24*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 25-29&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chapters 30-35&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;* Only half of the chapter is present in the respective episode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know what you think of Game Of Thrones in the comments...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introduction</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/04/10/introduction/"/>
   <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/04/10/introduction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my github pages. This will be my personal code blog site, or something of that sort. I will soon be transitioning this site to Jekyll for easier publishing and maybe move away from wordpress. (Done)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a proficient coder in PHP, working on various internal projects at SDSLabs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my current setup :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dell Inspiron 1545&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;T-6400 Intel Core 2 Duo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu Oneric Ocelot 11.10 (Default Primary OS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://elementaryos.org&quot;&gt;Elementary OS&lt;/a&gt; (Under Testing)&lt;/del&gt; Will be moving to Gnome Shell soon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://samurai.inguardians.org&quot;&gt;Samurai WTF&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://backtrack-linux.org&quot;&gt;Backtrack 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; for pen-tests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Moved from Windows after remaining a staunch supporter for 5 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to run apt-add-repository behind firewalls (#iitr)</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2011/04/01/run-apt-add-repo-behind-firewall/"/>
   <updated>2011-04-01T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2011/04/01/run-apt-add-repo-behind-firewall</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Copied from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.omgubuntu.co.uk/2011/01/how-to-add-repositories-to-ubuntu-from-behind-a-firewall/&quot;&gt;OMGUbuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press Alt-F2 and type &quot;gksu gedit /usr/lib/python2.6/dist-packages/softwareproperties/ppa.py&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find line 88, change &quot;keyserver.ubuntu.com&quot; to &quot;hkp://keyserver.ubuntu.com:80&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save and close&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Note that this is the default setting in Ubuntu Natty Narwhal (11.04), and was only applicable for Maverick or older versions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Random Stray Thoughts</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2010/05/25/what-the-hell-is-this/"/>
   <updated>2010-05-25T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2010/05/25/what-the-hell-is-this</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;[Editor's note: I found this scrawled across a a4 sheet in a classroom. The author drifts off way too much from his thinking to make any sense, but there were some things that I really liked. So I present them to you, unedited, random, and unexplainable thoughts of a genius. My comments are in brackets]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you are just destined to be where you are. You may try to veer off course, try to change it. But the end remains the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You.Here.Now&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The forces of Destiny seem too powerful to be stopped by you. So you keep on flowing. Further &amp;amp; further away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And time moves on
And its Now already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back at the choices you made, the crossroads you stood. The coincidences, accidents pile up and as you remember them you think - would you have chosen otherwise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But regardless of your answer you'd still be here, Now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And its only left to deal with the Now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Note: Now the author takes a swipe at history. lol]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since mankind learned to reason, the challenge had always been to tackle the Now. For tomorrow was forever being planned, partly in our own dreams, and partly in the garden of Destiny&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of the Past, it was just a multitude of feelings, a vault to choose from - Happy, sad, heartbreaking, exciting memories, remembrances, last words. The Past always walks besides us - sometimes haunting, crippling us down, and at times uplifting, encouraging, &amp;amp; maybe even expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so the challenge remains the the Now. What do you do with it? Go ahead and battle it head on - as you've been asked to, regardless of the consequences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For herein lies the path to greatness, the say - Keep Fighting. But is it the only path?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Note: Here on the author seems to get drifted far too much in his own thoughts, and does not care to explain very much. As a result much of the following is pretty self contradictory, and maybe even rubbish]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if there is another road. A road much less taken as Frost said. A road you know nothing about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if the present is not a choice? What if it is just a sequence of events to be played out from someone's memories, where you just play your part, and in-spite of what road you choose, you end up where you must.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you fight. And think. And fight with the Present [As if the present is a monster, you fool], believing that the Future can be changed, it can be manipulated, morphed into someone's likeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your head starts to pound with the effort. You decide to stop thinking. [Ahh. Finally, I was wondering how long I would have to keep up]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its clearing your head.
Then you look around you. [Reality, anyone?]
The Present closes in [Not again!!] You realize its not there to be defeated, or to win either.
It just is.
Just as you are.
And you close your eyes again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You start to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[I like the ending]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Worries Css Template</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2010/04/15/worries-css-template/"/>
   <updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2010/04/15/worries-css-template</id>
   <content type="html">Finally, from being a complete programmer to a designer as well, who can create a css template using Paint.Net. Photoshop is way too outlandish for me, you see. It wasn't easy, but it was definately fun. The template was based on a wallpaper by http://leon-gao.deviantart.com. The final template is still unnamed. Hope you all like it, and there is a demo available at http://nemo.criitique.in/worries . [caption id=&quot;attachment_55&quot; align=&quot;alignleft&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; caption=&quot;Worries Template&quot;]&lt;a href=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/simple2.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2010/04/simple2.png?w=300&quot; alt=&quot;Template&quot; title=&quot;Worries Template&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;208&quot; class=&quot;size-medium wp-image-55&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;[/caption]
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's Sailing</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2010/03/23/whats-sailing/"/>
   <updated>2010-03-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2010/03/23/whats-sailing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aboard The Nautilus, that is&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally decided to write a blog post for my non geek friends with affiliations ranging from DPs to BPs and the oblivious to all, but the elite few, GPs (Keep thinking, non_IITians). In midst of all the chapos, and ghissai(not me, of course), Nautilus has been, and will remain a lonely submarine beneath the ocean. And this has been the way for me in the past month. After a hefty piece of time where we were attacked by the mighty INS Cognizance (actually it was a retariation attack, because you see, Nautilus had won an event of theirs, a treasure hunt, and the mighty Cognizance, and the event organizers deemed the methods of my winning to be dishonest. (I had my reasons). But after that a hefty war at the seas resumed. I, had the luxury to dip underneath and avoid everything, once in a while. But rumours surrounded me, and I started to hear all sorts of things about me. And that is when the drama settled once and for all.(It ended with a 5k fine, if you need to know).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INS Cognizance is on its way for the end of its journey(Join it @ www.cognizance.org.in and 26-30 Mar, IITR). However I shall be busy participating somewhere else, Chaos '10, India's largest gaming extravaganza. I have assured INS Cognizance that Nautilus shall no longer be troubling them, but who knows with such waters, a collision may be unavoidable in the near future. And when that happens, I'm taking my warheads with me, just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news, I have been working on a couple of my own ideas, such as SMAC-I (Search Music Across Channel I), a Video Portal for Cinematography Section, IITRAANA.org, Counter Strike servers, the Intra Bhawan Gaming Tourney (which we won easily enough in AoE, NFS, as well as CS). Congrats to my clan mates. The net connectivity has been terrible here, and I've been derailed a few times along my route to Gmail. Among other news, Oh, and I won the second prize in srishti's dynamic website design, for LION- my twitter clone. I may or may not launch it, because you see, its just another clone. I also put up a new design for Criitique.in. Please check it out, and comment. I also posted a lot of pics and designs in Kriti , the DeviantArt clone for IITR. Check them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those outside IITR, the link for my web presence is http://nemo.criitique.in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some final few words in parting to all my frnds @ IITR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;@[Ex!$TeN$n3] - gl hf, gg :)&lt;br/&gt;
@LxG - 14,11&lt;br/&gt;
@alpha_Q - Better Luck Next Time&lt;br/&gt;
@17ninJa - Practice For Chaos&lt;br/&gt;
@bOb - fnatic lost to na'vi 2-0 (16-14, 16-13 in train, infy !)&lt;br/&gt;
@roomie - [insert silence here]&lt;br/&gt;
@xerxes,forsaken - nice team&lt;br/&gt;
@DArK_LOrD - i expected better&lt;br/&gt;
@Dead_Man - Welcome to LxG&lt;br/&gt;
@ll those I frGT - [Proxy laga dena plz]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And special thanks to DR. Lecter, General Hendrix for making the legend of Capt. Nemo a reality. If you ever need assistance in a cross atlantic trip, let me know. I may ship you till atlantis, after which you are responsible for yourself and your belongings :)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Learning PHP/mySQL Part 1</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2010/02/20/learning-phpmysql-part-1/"/>
   <updated>2010-02-20T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2010/02/20/learning-phpmysql-part-1</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past 2 months, Ive been learning PHP/mySQL as a great language. After helping out a lot of people, Ive decided to write a tutorial on using PHP/mySQL to create a cool website. For the entire duration of this tutorial, this is the list of softwares we will be working with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=XAMPP Server Lite version&quot;&gt;XAMPP Server Lite version&lt;/a&gt; (to get apache &amp;amp; mySQL)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;www.mediafire.com/?4eemynbynjw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dreamweaver CS4&lt;/a&gt; (For Template Support). Alternatively use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Microsoft Expression Web 3&quot;&gt;Microsoft Expression Web 3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Notepad++&quot;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt; (Its a cool editor)&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=PHP Manual&quot;&gt;PHP Manual&lt;/a&gt; (download the full html version)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The website we will be developing is called Artemis Fowl Files (AFF for short). It is a small website with several features that we shall develop over the length of the tutorial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Installing PHP &amp;amp; mySQL using XAMPP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PHP is a server side scripting language. Which means that PHP is run on the web server itself. For example any PHP script running at Google.com will remain on the server, and not reach you (the client). By contrast, JavaScript runs on the client side, i.e. any JS code must be transmitted to the client before being executed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how a basic PHP script actually runs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;PHP source File &amp;gt; PHP Parser (running on the web server) &amp;gt; Becomes an HTML file &amp;gt; HTML File sent to Client&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which means that the PHP source file is run on the server, which converts the file to a pre-calculated html file, which is then sent to the client. Lets write some basic php coding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1:  &amp;lt;HTML&amp;gt;
2:  &amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt;Sample PHP File&amp;lt;/TITLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/HEAD&amp;gt;
3:  &amp;lt;BODY&amp;gt;
4:  &amp;lt;?php
5:  echo &quot;This is a sample PHP File&quot;;
6:  ?&amp;gt;
7:  &amp;lt;/BODY&amp;gt;
8:  &amp;lt;/HTML&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic context of PHP is that the only code that is considered PHP is that covered between &amp;lt;?PHP and ?&amp;gt; blocks. Anything outside these is neglected and remains the same(i.e. it is not run on the server). The echo command sends the text string to the html file. All this means that the file received by the client will look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1:  &amp;lt;HTML&amp;gt;&amp;lt;HEAD&amp;gt;&amp;lt;TITLE&amp;gt;Sample PHP File&amp;lt;/TITLE&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/HEAD&amp;gt;
2:  &amp;lt;BODY&amp;gt;
3:  This is a sample PHP File
4:  &amp;lt;/BODY&amp;gt;
5:  &amp;lt;/HTML&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what you will get if you ran the script on a test server. But before doing that we must install XAMPP, and do some basic setup stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download, and Extract XAMPPlite.exe anywhere in your computer. Go to where you installed it and run setup_xampp.bat. This will automatically start the Apache Server, and the mysql Server by default. Also try tinkering with XAMPP-Control and see what runs it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now open your web browser (Firefox/Chrome is preferred) and open &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1&lt;/a&gt;. This IP address is a loopback IP address and always refers to this computer itself (yours). Now you should see a XAMPP splash screen. Go ahead and explore. As of now, what youve achieved is this : Installed Apache and the mySQL server. Now we need to change the settings for mysql. Open &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1/security/xamppsecurity.php&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1/security/xamppsecurity.php&lt;/a&gt; and change the mysql root password(its blank by default). Also set a password on the xampp directory, so that others cant access these settings. Remember the mysql root password, for it will be useful later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the part where we actually sit down to write some code. We will be developing the mysql parts in the next segment. However we still need to do some other little things before we reach that part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Creating The Dreamweaver Template&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, call me lazy, but I dont like designing themes, and CSS for my websites. I usually use a free one. And for the rest of this tutorial, I assume you will do the same. We need to create a Dreamweaver website using a readymade CSS Template. To get a template head on to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecsstemplates.org&quot;&gt;http://www.freecsstemplates.org&lt;/a&gt;. I choose &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freecsstemplates.org/preview/reckoning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; template. Feel free to choose anything. It does not really matter which, but take care not to download a three column template, because what we will be developing is quite basic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a directory called artemis inside htdocs folder(found inside xampp). Extract the css template files to the artemis folder such that the index.html file is inside xampp\artemis . Now head to your browser and open &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1/artemis&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1/artemis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all went well, you should now see the template theme. Now we must convert this css template into a Dreamweaver template. Open the index.html file in Dreamweaver. We have to mark certain areas that we intend to edit in each document as editable. For instance the top header in each document must remain the same and would not be editable. But the sidebar content may need to change as per each page on our site. Taking this further the footer will be the same for each page. To create an editable region, just select a sample text from the main text (the one on that looks like the blog entry) and right click &amp;gt;Templates-&amp;gt;Create Editable Region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreamweaver will give a warning that the current document will be converted to a template. That is what we want. Give a name to the region(lets call it main). Now delete everything other than this main region from the right column(ie the blog entry column. You may need to switch to the split view to cleanly delete the html markup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly create another editable region for the sidebar. Remember to delete everything else in the sidebar as well. Now there is something to Dreamweaver which requires you to create a site before you can create a template. So go to Site Menu and click on New Site. Choose a site name (Artemis) and enter the correct web address where you can access index.html (&lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1/artemis&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1/artemis&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost/artemis&quot;&gt;http://localhost/artemis&lt;/a&gt;). Tell Dreamweaver that you want to use a server technology (PHP mySQL). Choose edit and test locally(because we dont yet have access to an external web server).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once youve created a site, you can save the web template. (Ctrl S). Currently no templates exist in our web site, So we will create one and call it main template. If Dreamweaver asks you to update links, press yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we will create our basic home page using this template. Press Ctrl+N to create a new page. On the left choose Page from Template, Choose the site as Artemis, and the template as well. Press Create, and viola, we have our homepage. You may see that the heading, footer, and links are not changeable, because theyre not defined as editable in the template. However the regions you choose to be editable are marked as such. Try writing some basic text in the sidebar and in the main content screen, and then save the file as index.php.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now open &lt;a href=&quot;http://127.0.0.1/artemis/&quot;&gt;http://127.0.0.1/artemis/&lt;/a&gt; in your computer, and be greeted with your newest creation. It' is still, as of now, a static site, with links that dont work and no dynamism, but we will make it better in the next part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you had trouble following this tutorial anywhere feel free to post comments, or tweet me @capt_n3m0. I will be happy to reply. Further if you feel that you missed something, here is my work for you to compare with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;//#todo add link to zip file here&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nautilus : Behind The Curtains</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2009/12/04/nautilus-behind-the-curtains/"/>
   <updated>2009-12-04T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2009/12/04/nautilus-behind-the-curtains</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone looks at my laptops screen, and asks me is that Windows 7 ? and I reply each of them with the same answer No. I have not yet moved to 7, because of various reasons, which I am not going to explain over here, but lets just say that Im still clinging to dear old Vista. I dont really have much of a trouble with Vista as many people have said. I work blazingly fast with Vista, which is what it is all about. As an operating system, it is expected to help me get my job done, not do everything by itself. And this is where my software listing comes into view. Since everyone have those how the heck did you do that? moments when they look at me doing stuff, I decided to publish a listing of some of my favourite applications that I use so that I may redirect you to safe spot where you may choose things as you like. This listing may not suite your way of working, however you might find a gem or two along the way. This is not a listing of all softwares that I use. Rather just a collection of cool tools that I think every Windows user must be using. If you think youve found that killer-app for doing things, do let me know in the comments. Ill be listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Dell Dock&quot; href=&quot;http://www.delldock.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;  style=&quot;display:inline;border-width:0;margin:0 0 0 15px;&quot; src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/delldock.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;143&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Dell Dock : &lt;/strong&gt;I just love this tools and its ability to divide the applications that I use into categories. It doesnt take much of a screen estate, and takes me where ever I ask it to. With the ability to assign custom icons, and add separators/categories etc, it is more than an average dock, its my favourite dock. On the downside, this is only for Dell Computers, and comes preinstalled. However you can download it from &lt;a title=&quot;DellDock.com&quot; href=&quot;http://www.delldock.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if you didnt get it with your dell systems. Non dell users may be interested in RK Launcher, a freeware dock that simulates Mac Dashboard, and does a pretty good job. There was another version of Dell Dock (2.x which has yet to be released on the website, but was available to Dell Studio buyers, with new and better icons. Drop by a comment if you need it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Windows Sidebar : &lt;/strong&gt;Another tool I find myself using frequently is the Windows Sidebar, with 3-4 gadgets that are absolutely essential to me, such as the NowPlaying, MultiMeter, and the Top Processes gadget. A key shortcut to remember here is Win+Space which pops up my sidebar. Gadgets are a quick way to organize yourself, and keep a check on other things, like you schedule(Date Time), twitter(Twadged), quick launching apps, direct search among other things. Most users underestimate their usage and restrict themselves to the Clock and Slideshow gadget. Go ahead and search for them, see if you can find a gadget that matches what youd like.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/taskbar.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;  style=&quot;display:inline;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;border-width:0;&quot; title=&quot;My Taskbar&quot; src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/taskbar_thumb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;My Taskbar&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;77&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Quick Launch : &lt;/strong&gt;Not many would regard this as a tool, however this gives one a productivity boost. Try putting your favourite tools in the Quick Launch, and see if that helps you a bit, between searching for that app in Start Menu, or clicking it right where its clickable. Also try increasing the size of the Quick Launch, by Unlocking the taskbar, right click-&amp;gt;View-&amp;gt;Large Icons. That really looks cool!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Internet Download Manager&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet Download Manager&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; :&lt;/strong&gt;My personal favourite download manager. Others that you may be interested in are : Orbit , &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=DownThemAll&quot;&gt;DownThemAll&lt;/a&gt;! ( a firefox extension). Helps me keep a track on what Im downloading right now, and speed benefits are downright clear. I also like its feature to capture downloads from any application, so I dont have to wait for those updates taking forever to download. Downloads using batch files, schedulers, and even turns off your computer when its done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voidtools.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; : &lt;/strong&gt;I should have put this above all in the list. This is such a good tool, I cannot overestimate its importance. What it basically does is searches Everything. The tool does not index file contents/properties, and only maintains an index of file names. As such it is blazingly fast, and searches all my applications/music/files damn quick. With an efficient shortcut(such as Win+S), youre on your way to becoming a windows power user. On the downside, once you start using this real frequently, you tend to get a little disorganized putting stuff everywhere, knowing you will find it with Everything. Heres a link to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voidtools.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. (MUST USE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Browsers :&lt;/strong&gt; In browsers, I currently use a combination of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Google Chrome&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Firefox&quot;&gt;Firefox &lt;/a&gt;as my primary browser, updated to the latest dev build, and last stable beta respectively. Both of these are great, and I prefer Firefox with its huge base of extensions available. And if someone is out there using IE still, please switch immediately. Firefox is such a great way to browse with, and Chrome such a ease on the eyes. Its hard for me to pick between the two, Ill rather wait and watch over the next year, where each one stands. Safari and Opera come a distant second for me with Safari being the better one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Tools :&lt;/strong&gt; I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=7-zip&quot;&gt;7-zip&lt;/a&gt; for compression purposes, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=CCleaner&quot;&gt;CCleaner &lt;/a&gt;to rid my computer of junk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Defraggler&quot;&gt;Defraggler &lt;/a&gt;to defragment my hard disk, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Recuva&quot;&gt;Recuva &lt;/a&gt;from the same company to restore those accidently deleted files.Another tool I would mention here is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=GoodSync&quot;&gt;GoodSync&lt;/a&gt; which i use to sync my usb drive and my Documents. I also use it to organize my Start Menu, using a Dock folder in my Desktop, which i sync to the Start Menu. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Dropbox&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; is the best tool I use for my syncing purposes, between different computers. It offers 2 gb for starters, and all the sync is on the fly, meaning you just copy things to your Dropbox folder, which is automatically synced to all of your computer. It is also a great way to sync your projects with different people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multimedia : &lt;/strong&gt;I prefer Windows Media Player 11 for audio, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=VLC&quot;&gt;VLC &lt;/a&gt;for video viewing. With my NowPlaying gadget, and GTalk in sync with WMP, its easy to change tracks, and let others know what youre listening to. I also use Zune occasionally when Im in the mood of a pure music experience. Pictures are pretty easy to manage with Windows built in Photo Gallery, or its live version. Also check out picasa, googles free photo management tool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Office Tools :&lt;/strong&gt;I am currently using a Technical Preview Beta of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Office 2010&quot;&gt;Office 2010&lt;/a&gt;, for documents,presentations. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Notepad++&quot;&gt;Notepad++&lt;/a&gt; for text and code editing, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Foxit PDF Reader&quot;&gt;Foxit PDF Reader&lt;/a&gt; for ebooks, and reading stuff, which is way faster, and smaller than that Bloated Adobe Acrobat Reader. I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Windows Live Writer,&quot;&gt;Windows Live Writer&lt;/a&gt;, which offers a lot of plugins to edit posts, including this one.Offline gmail and Google Docs capability is way cooler than you think. Do try it out&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/mse.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;  style=&quot;display:inline;border-width:0;margin:0 0 0 20px;&quot; title=&quot;mse&quot; src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/mse_thumb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;mse&quot; width=&quot;306&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Anti Virus :&lt;/strong&gt; This is one of the areas where I am consulted the most. Which antivirus to use? Well I would recommend you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Kaspersky&quot;&gt;Kaspersky &lt;/a&gt;if youre ready to shell out some money with a little slowing down to your system or use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Microsoft Security Essentials&quot;&gt;Microsoft Security Essentials&lt;/a&gt; which I currently use. It is quick, doesnt hog down my system, stops real time protection when i want it to, excludes some of my dangerous folders from being scanned and nuked, updates itself, detects almost any virus I dare to throw at it, and looks neat. On the downside, however it is just minimal, with no support for hosts file scanning, white listing, firewall, cookie management, user control, among other high level stuff that other anti viruses offer. But I like it, have been consistently using it for last 3 months, and am pretty sure Im virus free. It does have a catch : you must own a valid, genuine copy of Windows to use the tool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Tools :&lt;/strong&gt; Security Tools includes those nifty small programs that help me keep my computer safe, and sound. This listing comprises of tools I would suggest to the average user, I personally use a combination more than the following tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=AMPAWSmasherX&quot;&gt;AMPAWSmasherX&lt;/a&gt; :Stops antiviruses from using your pen drive as a medium, by blocking that autorun.inf file. You might not find the tool easily available for download, but if you do, its a pretty good one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=SpyBot Search &amp;amp; Destroy&quot;&gt;SpyBot Search &amp;amp; Destroy&lt;/a&gt; : This is a one stop protection for all malware. Keep the definitions updated, however, and you will find that infections are pretty easy to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=HiJack This&quot;&gt;HiJack This&lt;/a&gt; : Must use every 2 weeks or so. Shows you anything that has been changed from normal settings on your computer,and allows you to change it to default. Use carefully, as it may cause instability on your system later on, as it is quite a powerful tool, and if you dont know what to do, generate your report, and post it online in one of the help forums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=WinPatrol&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;  style=&quot;display:inline;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;border-width:0;&quot; title=&quot;winpatrol&quot; src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/winpatrol.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;winpatrol&quot; width=&quot;377&quot; height=&quot;168&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt; WinPatrol&lt;/a&gt; : This is also a must-use program for securing your computer against anything unwanted which may include viruses, malware, additional crapware, fake windows services, hidden files, and the like. This is basically a watchdog(Scotty), which keeps a watch on any new startup programs (my favorite), and file extension changes, and new services and the like. If Scotty detects an unwanted change in your system, it barks and reminds you of the change and asks you if youd like to keep it. It also allows you to add/remove/delay your startup programs list, and is my favourite program of the lot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Tools : &lt;/strong&gt;I would just like to recommend some more everyday helpful tools to you, in no particular order. Try them out, you might like them or not, but they are definitely worth checking out : &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=TeraCopy&quot;&gt;TeraCopy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=AveThumbnail Resizer&quot;&gt;AveThumbnail Resizer&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=TuneUpUtilities&quot;&gt;TuneUpUtilities&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=VistaGlazz&quot;&gt;VistaGlazz&lt;/a&gt;(must use for including transparency in title bar, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=appwiz.cpl&quot;&gt;appwiz.cpl&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=WinBubbles&quot;&gt;WinBubbles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Privoxy&quot;&gt;Privoxy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=TaskBar Shuffle&quot;&gt;TaskBar Shuffle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Paint.NET&quot;&gt;Paint.NET&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=DupFiles&quot;&gt;DupFiles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=WinDirStat&quot;&gt;WinDirStat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=OverDisk&quot;&gt;OverDisk&lt;/a&gt; (both for checking disk usage), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=PMenu&quot;&gt;PMenu&lt;/a&gt;(especially if you use portable programs in you usb drive, or for assigning Win+ hotkeys to programs, like I use Win+P=paint, N=notepad), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=I'm Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=Nero Free version&quot;&gt;Nero Free version&lt;/a&gt; among others (Refer below for a complete listing)
&lt;a href=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/pm.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;  style=&quot;display:inline;margin-left:0;margin-right:0;border-width:0;&quot; title=&quot;PowerMenu&quot; src=&quot;http://captn3m0.files.wordpress.com/2009/12/pm_thumb.jpg&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; alt=&quot;PowerMenu&quot; width=&quot;244&quot; height=&quot;195&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looks : &lt;/strong&gt;Looks are necessary part of making your computer shine out in the crowd. And I use the least required programs for that purpose. Using Tune Ups styler to change my login Screen, and my personal wallpaper collection which I shuffle through using Vortec Wallpaper changer, a utility i built. Using Vista Glazz to patch my theme files to support 3rd party themes, I use themes downloaded from deviantArt. I also iconized my taskbar, for efficiently managing taskbar, and changed the quick launch icon size to large(looks cool). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=QTTab Bar&quot;&gt;QTTab Bar&lt;/a&gt; is also a cool addition to Windows installing tabbed browsing in Windows Explorer. The current theme I use is Cleaero, and it gives me some cool transparency. I also use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?btnI=Im Feeling Lucky&amp;amp;q=PowerMenu&quot;&gt;PowerMenu&lt;/a&gt;(another must use)for adding transparency, or changing priority of any window. I love it when my firefox window is transparent and Im browsing while watching a video in the background. That is damn-right as cool as it gets without using Windows Blinds. And choosing the coolest gadgets can make all the difference, so see if you can find the right ones!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Complete Listing of Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The above was just a partial listing of the programs that I use. I generated a file listing of all the sofwares that I using four different methods. All of these are in text files, that you may use, with one exception. The easiest one is a tree map generated for my Dock Folder(list.dock). I generate a listing of all exe files inside my program files(which may not be complete since many like Chrome are installed in userdata folder). This one is renamed as list.exe.txt. Next I generate a listing of all installed programs using Hijack this!, called list.hijack. Another one was compiled using windirstat (list.windirstat). Using OverDisk I generated a virtual folder view of my Apps directory(this ones huge at 2.x mb). Then I zipped them up and post them here. Browse through them, you might find a lesser used unknown app here. Especially check out the tiny folder. It is literally legendary, with tons of stuff! And one more thing, use OverDisk to open the ovd file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Here  &lt;a href=&quot;http://dl.dropbox.com/u/1766113/List.zip&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;Listings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list was composed by Capt. Nemo as a recommendation for non-power users of Windows. You are free to check out any of the programs, most of them are freeware, if not open source, and do not pose a harm to your computer. However if anything happens to your computer by these tools I am NOT responsible for the usage of the tool. And I try to use open-source/freeware tools as far as possible. If you use a commercial tool, do remember to pay the author, and stand against piracy. Otherwise use Free as in Beer tools like me!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gamers Saga - Games to play and not to play</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2009/11/23/gamers-saga-games-to-play-and-not-to-play/"/>
   <updated>2009-11-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2009/11/23/gamers-saga-games-to-play-and-not-to-play</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This article has been bubbling in my mind for quite some time, and Ive decided to steam it off. There are games that you must play, like Mario or Contra. Then there are games that you play (Counter Strike, AoE). Some games you wish you could play (Assassins Creed, Far Cry). Games you should play (Braid, Minesweeper, Spore). And finally come the games you must NEVER play (Farmville, World Of Warcraft, Mafia Wars, School Of Magic and the like). Why this categorization? Because I recently decided to leave School Of Magic on facebook after a week long affair where I reached lvl 15, and was about to get into thick of things as they say. Why? Because I realized that SOM is not a true game. A game is supposed to be entertaining, and indulgive. If it tells me to do something, I must do it because I take interest in it. Not to get ahead of my peers.&amp;#160; I recently came across an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smh.com.au/news/articles/ethical-dilemmas/2007/09/19/1189881577195.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jonathan_Blow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jonathan Blow&lt;/a&gt;, my favourite game designer (Braid). He opened my mind to the fact that &lt;strong&gt;A Game is a form of art&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not agree with this statement right now, but consider James Camerons Avatar, which looks so close to real, yet is live 3d. It does look kind of gamer-ish, doesnt it? And we all agree that cinemas, and literature are a part of our culture, part of our art. But as movies get closer to games(Resident Evil, Prince Of Persia), the same is happening the other way around. Games are becoming a part of our art culture. Games like Bio-Shock, and Fear portray the doomed versions of our future. The designer behind these games did not just say, lets make another FPS, where you kill everything that moves (that was Doom 1,2 by the way). They decided to create a realistic storyline, and a better game play. That is as innovative as it takes to get the feel of the game to the player.&amp;#160;&amp;#160; Let us now take up some of these categories I defined quickly.&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games You Must Play : &lt;/strong&gt;These are the kind of games, that each of us has played. They remind us of how we first stared at that green background trying to figure out the next play in Solitaire. Or the joy of ducking under the dragon and touching that axe in Mario. These games still remind us about the giant leap that the gaming industry has taken. For Dave, Wolf-3d, Roadrash, we have reached graphics quality that surpasses HD (Call Of Duty Modern Warfare 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games You Play : &lt;/strong&gt;Skip this if you arent a gamer. If youre one, well you know the games Im talking about. Nothing beats taking a frag with a deagle. Other than maybe shouting 14 before all those AoE games. Its the thrill, and excitement, and your love of the game that keeps you glued to the seat. I wont call these games entirely unethical, because the game play here is fair enough, and exciting. You know what youre doing, and why. And its not just because of that score, or frag. It is also because of the satisfaction that you get after that frag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games You Wish You Could Play : &lt;/strong&gt;Sometimes you Graphics Card isnt all that powerful, or you just cant find a torrent/download link for the game. Sometimes 10GB games do seem big. And sometimes, as in the case of FIESTA, the game hasnt been launched for PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games You Should Play : &lt;/strong&gt;These are the games that really matter. That form of the core of my games are art theory. Games like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.braid-game.com&quot;&gt;Braid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hemispheregames.com/osmos/&quot;&gt;Osmos&lt;/a&gt;, Minesweeper, Prince Of Persia (not all), Tomb Raider (again not all parts). These games take you into their own world, where you get to learn, listen, think, and observe. Where you play the game because its exciting, and fun, and you want to play it. Not because someone is offering you a level up if you click on a button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Games You Should Never Play : &lt;/strong&gt;If once is not enough, I repeat, &lt;strong&gt;Stay away from these games&lt;/strong&gt;. Please, these hacked up versions of the same code, or sometimes game idea, do not deserve to be called as games. Mafia Wars, Restaurant, Cafe Shop, and all of those mindless facebook games come here. And so do War Of Warcraft, Travian, NFS Pro Street(that was just a bad game). These so-called-games

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;do nothing to entertain you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;offer you nothing but just-another-level-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;never teach something (play braid, youll understand what I mean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have nothing interesting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then what is the reason that they are so hyped, and most played MMORPGs? The reason is lack of better games. Lack of games that exist on facebook and is not-another-clone-of-mafia-wars. Lack of games that adhere to strict design ideas. Do not take me wrong. There are some serious game designers who are talented, but the truth is that they are forced to make what sells, and what sells is Mafia Wars. Unfortunately. And these people are forced to work for such games. Wasting their talent on such mindless games. And if all of this wasnt enough read this quote by the CEO of Mafia Wars :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew that i wanted to control my destiny, so I knew I needed revenues, right, fucking, now. Like I needed revenues now. So I funded the company myself but I did every horrible thing in the book to, just to get revenues right away. I mean we gave our users poker chips if they downloaded this zwinky toolbar which was like, I dont know, I downloaded it once and couldnt get rid of it. &lt;em&gt;laughs&lt;/em&gt; We did anything possible just to just get revenues so that we could grow and be a real businessSo control your destiny. So that was a big lesson, controlling your business. So by the time we raised money we were profitable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the entire story on facebook gaming scams &lt;a href=&quot;http://consumerist.com/5400720/mafia-wars-ceo-brags-about-scamming-users-from-day-one&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. And if youre with me, try picking up some better titles instead of playing these nonsense games on FB&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome Aboard The Nautilus</title>
   <link href="http://captnemo.in/blog/2009/11/19/welcome/"/>
   <updated>2009-11-19T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://capt.nemo/blog/2009/11/19/welcome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first real post on my brand new blog at wordpress, and quite seriously, Im thrilled to get a new start. I hope this project would flourish unlike many of the other things I took up (&lt;a href=&quot;http://kasiasi.blogspot.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kasiasi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.papercut.co.nr&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Papercut&lt;/a&gt;,). I have not yet completely given up on Papercut, and I really liked the Google Sites interface, but posting online, and editing it takes time. So this is my first attempt at publishing offline edited work, using Windows Live Writer. Ill try to use other options as well, and let you know which I like best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for some blogging stuff. Whats happening aboard the Nautilus? What is the Nautilus, and who is Capt. Nemo ? Let me answer these these three questions in my introductory post first. It all began in Kota, when I was a JEE student vying to enter the holiest institutes of the country, the IIT. And what I was doing there was, well studying and playing Age Of Empires, with my two best friends, Sankalp (aka General Hendrix) and Shundi (aka DR. Lecter). And our trio was one of the most feared AoE clans in Kota. We were playing together in perfect team play, and knew every counter there was to know, and every fact in the guidebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was just a little flaw, I didnt have a name. I used to play under various names, like Godfather, Eragon, and of course Harry Potter, but none of these stuck, and I was still nameless. I was like Maerad in the The Gift, looking for her true name. That night I went sleepless, and searched my inner soul for my True name. Both of my teammates already had titles (one doctor, and other a general), so I decided I would get one as well. And after storming by brain for all the books Ive read, and all those movies, I settled for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Capt._Nemo&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Capt. Nemo&lt;/a&gt;. Where did I get the name from? It was from a book called 20,000 Leagues under the sea, by the immortal master of Sc-Fi, Jules Verne. The character of Capt. Nemo was one of most mysterious you could ever see. And one of the most brilliant. And I got it when Id read it for the umpteenth time, Capt. Nemo wasnt an enigma. Just because he didnt fit into the definition of a hero doesnt make him a villain. I could go on and on about the character, but that would take up space, which Im determined to use to answer the other 2 questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the Nautilus. I call pretty much everything I own, the Nautilus. Why? Because that was Capt. Nemos masterpiece. His submarine, and the very first, at least on paper.And my room and my laptop are labelled as Nautilus . And this blog is the path that I follow Aboard The Nautilus. That brings me to the third question, what Ive been doing lately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lately Ive been playing around with PHP a lot, and mind you it is really cool. I might post some of my experiences with PHP later on. And the reason Ive been playing with PHP is because Ive been working on my own website(its not exactly mine, its under Web Designing Section, IITR, but Ive written 95% of its code). Ill be launching soon, under a limited beta, so keep watching. Ive also been working on the second issue of Criitique, an e-magazine for the youth. With kick-ass articles you are sure to like it. Do check it at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.criitique.com&quot;&gt;www.criitique.com&lt;/a&gt;. Playing Age Of Empires is now a daily affair for me now, and Ive been working my way up and down my timings. For those interested, my timings currently are 13,20,35 with 27,28-29 pop. Ive been tweeting a lot, and I still dont know why the twitter fad isnt catching up in India. Twitter is fast, and easy, so why dont people use it? Any ideas? Let me know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ive also got to study, with my end sems coming up, and this seems to be the time to do it. Got any more brainstorming ideas to work on? Wanna work with me? Join the fun Aboard The Nautilus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an update, Windows Live Writer refused to connect to my blog and I finnaly used BlogDesk to publish my post. And I also tried Qumana, and wBlogger, and FYI, none of them work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
  
</feed>
